I won't talk to you. You will also leave me.
من ديه باشما صحبت نميكنم. شما مي خواهيد منو ترک کنيد.
Grandfather too is leaving.
در بز هم ميخواد بره.
When you grow wings, you too will fly away.
هنامي که بال هاتون رشد كنه، بيش از حد ازاينجا دور ميشيد.
Emperor Chandragupta Maurya has embraced Jainism...
امراتور قصد دارن  Chandragupta Maurya
for which he is abdicating, giving up his throne...
كه همه اموال خود را
his kingdom and his people.
بين مردمش تقسيم كند
Grandfather, Asoka has taken your sword. He says it is his.
در بز آشوك شمشير رونميده ميه مال خودمه.
You are leaving me, but the sword is mine.
شما كه ميريد ، لاقل شمشير رو بمن بديد.
Asoka, my son, this is not just a sword.
اين،Asoka، سر م، فقط يک شمشير نيست.
It's a demon.
اين شيطان است.
When drawn, it hungers blood. It doesn't see friend or foe.
وقتي کشيده مي شود ، فقط خون بجا ميماند . دوست ودشمن هم نميشناسد
It sees only blood.Just blood.
تنها يزي كه ازش ميبيني خون  است .
Before it can do more harm, let us get rid of it.
قبل از اينكه آسيب ببيني، اجازه بده  از آن خلاص شيم.
''This is not just a sword. It's a demon.
"اين فقط يک شمشير نيست. اين شيطان است.
It doesn't see friend or foe. It sees only blood.Just blood.''
تو اين كار دوست ودشمن نميشناسد. تنها خون ميبيند. ''
The Takshila army is mightier than ours.
جناب آشوک , ارتش آشيلاک .به ما رسيده
Half our army has not reached.
نيمي از ارتش ما هنوز  نرسيده .
General Shivrath, hasn't reached...
جنرال شيرواک ، رسيده ...
or my brother Susima has not let it reach?
يا برادر من Susima اجازه نمي ده به آن دست يابيد؟
We will not lose. For even if wars are fought on battlefields...
ما نمي خواهيم بازنده باشيم براي مبارزه بايد...
they are won by the mind.
از مغزتون استفاده کنيد.
Takshila army, keep moving.
Takshila ، نه داشتن ارتش  در حال حرکت.
Prince, Takshila army is advancing.
ارتش تاکشيل داره به طرف ما مياد، شاهزاده.
Stop them, General, by force or by deceit.
آنها بايد متوقف بشن ژنرال ه با زور، ه با فريب
Their army has been halved. Now they want to surrender.
ارتش تاکشيل نصف شده وميخواهند تسليم شوند قربان.
The enemy deserves a chance. Don't you agree, General?
،دشمن سزاوار شانسه. آيا شما نميخواهيد توافق کنيم، ژنرال؟
Takshila's flags are down. We want to surrender, Prince.
تاکشيل ايه رم را به نشانه تسليم فرستادند.
Our army has laid down their weapons.
ارتش ما، سلاح هاي خود را زمين ذاشتند..
Takshila kneels before Magadha.
وتاکشيل خواسته باهاش همکاري کنيد.
Surrender to me.
تسليم شو.
The weapon is with me.
اين يه اسلحه است.
That is no weapon.
اين سلاح نيست .
This is a weapon.
اين سلاح است.
The head that won't bow to us will be cut off.
سري که به مهاراجه  تعظيم نكنه قطع خواهد شد.
What are you taking with you?
ي داري؟
Nothing.
هيي.
All that and you say it's nothing?
اينهمه ل شتت قايم کردي اونوقت ميي هيي
Give us some of it.
يه کم از اينها به منم ميدي ؟.
Should i?
به تو؟
That's too much.
تو خيلي خشني دختر.
Want more? -No, we'll share it.
شما هم ميخواهيد؟ نه ، همان يکي رو بين همدير تقسيم ميکنيم.
You better smarten up.
شما کجاييد .
Prince Asoka is arriving, victorious from Takshila.
راج کمار آشوک برتاکشيل يروز شده وهمين الان وارد شد
The stars never lie. -Damn your stars.
ستاره ها هرز دروغ . نمين. لعنت به ستاره هاو خودت
Susima's mother is King Bindusara's favored queen.
مادر Susima کين Bindusara مورد علاقه ملکه.
With her around no one will dare eye the throne.
با وجود او هيکس جرات نداره به تاج وتخت نظر داشته باشه
And what of Asoka's mother, Queen Dharma?
مادر آشوک هم ملکه دارما است؟
She is less of a Queen and more of a slave.
او که به ملکه شباهتي نداره بيشتر به يک برده شبيه.
Only Prince Susima can claim the throne.
فقط شاهزاده مي تواند ادعاي تاج و تخت کند Susima.
Where is Susima?
کجاست ؟ Susima
General Shivrath. The great General Shivrath.
معروف Shivrath. بزر Shivrath .
It is you who suggested that Asoka be sent to Takshila.
اين يشنهاد شمابود که يروز ميشهAsoka به Takshila .
You said he would lose, didn't you?
شما  او را  دست کم رفتيد وهمه يز رو از دست داديد    درست نيست؟،
''Send him with half the army and he won't return alive.''
او  با نصف ارتش رفته وزنده برشته
You said so, right?
شما فتيد، درسته ؟
Then what is this?
س اين يه ؟
What do we do with you now? You have failed.
،حالا با يه آدم شکست خورده يکار بايد کرد ؟
What is the fate of a defeated soldier?
سرنوشت يک سرباز شکست خورده يست؟
Let me be sentenced to death.
اجازه دهيد من رو اعدام کنند.
Defeat hasn't crushed the warrior's ego. He still holds his head high.
جنجوي شکست خورده ما مخواهد سرش بالاي دار باشه وبالا رو ببينه
I want him to lower his head.
اما من مي خواهم که سرش ايين ايش رو ببينه .
These arms and medals belong to Magadha's proud army.
اين سلاح ها و مدال استMagadhaمتعلق به ارتش ر افتخار .
Do you think you deserve all this?
فکر مي کنيد لياقت اينها رو داريد؟
No.
نه.
Take them off.
به آنها ناه کن
Strip him naked.
لباساشو در بياريد
Here, brother. The General is now ready for war.
شما اينجا ييد، برادر. ژنرال ميخواد شمارو ببينه.
He has lowered his head.
حالا سرش ايينه .
Now you can kill him.
بکشيدش.
You don't know Asoka. i have tried to kill him all of eleven times.
تو آشوک رو نميشناسي .من يازده بار تلاش کردم اورا بکشم اما نشد.
Don't worry. Asoka will die for sure.
نران نباشيد آشوک حتما خواهد مرد.
You know your job well.
تو ميتوني اين کاررو به خوبي انجام بدي.
i advise you to attack him while he is bathing in the river...
به شما توصيه ميکنم موقع حمام کردن کارش راتمام کنيد
when he is most vulnerable...
بهترين زمان...
emerging out of the water, then...
زمانيه که سرش رو از آب بيرون مياره... آن وقت
All i want is to know who sent you.
نران نباش ميخوام بفهمم کي تورو فرستاده.
Long live King Susima.
Susimaزنده باد ادشاه .
You missed. Again.
برادر دوباره, دوباره.
See, there isn't a scratch on me.
هيي نيست ببينيد ، حتي يک خراش هم روي من نيفتاده.
i want you to leave Magadha. -Why should i?
رو ترک کني Magadhaتوبايد . -- را بايد؟
The coming siX moonless nights are not auspicious for you.
توي ستاره ها شبهاي خوشي براي تو نيست.
My good or bad luck rests with my sword.
شانس خوب يا بد من سر جاي خودمم شمشير هم با منه.
Is that your wish? i run away? i'm no coward.
دوست داري من فرار کنم ؟ وهمه بن ترسيد؟
i'm not afraid of anyone, Mother. -But i'm afraid.
من از کسي نميترسم، مادر. -- اما من مي ترسم.
How can you know a mother's pain? 9 months i nurtured you in my womb.
طور ميتوني بفهمي من ه حسي دارم ؟ 9ماه تورو توي رحم خودم نهداري ميکردم
i am your son, Mother. i will understand your pain.
مادر , من سر شماهستم. من ناراحتي شما را درک ميکنم.
Even if i have to carry you around for nine months.
حتي ار من  شما را 9 ماه به اين طرف و آنطرف حمل نکردم .
Let me know your pain, Mother.
بذاريد درد را حس کنم ، مادر  .
You are right, Mother. Nine moments maybe...
شما راست مييد مادر براي 9 ثانيه هم سخته
but for nine months, you're too heavy.
ه برسه به 9ماه، ونکه شما بيش از حد سنين هستيد.
Don't change the subject, will you leave or not?
موضوع را عوض نکن، اينجا رو ترک ميکني يا نه؟
I heard you. I promise, Mother.
من به حرفت وش ميدم ،مادر قول مي دم .
Asoka. -I promise, Mother.
آشوک قول ميدم , مادر
I promise, pundit-ji.
قول مي دم،مادر قول ميدم .
How are you? We've not met since your return.
حال شما طوره؟ از زمان بازشت شما رو ملاقات نکرديم.
I heard that someone tried to kill you.
من شنيده ام که کساني سعي کردن شمارو بکشند.
Someone did try to kill me, yet again.
بله , هنوز هم قصد انجام اين کار رو دارند
Who would want that, Asoka?
کي ميتونه باشه آشوک ؟
A fool that misses each time.
يه احمقه که نميدونه هنوز زمانش نرسيده.
Beware, Asoka. One shouldn't underestimate the enemy.
,مراقب باشيد آشوک . نبايد دشمن را دست کم رفت.
He who faces me with a sword is my enemy.
هرکي بخواهدبمن صدمه بزنه باشمشير من طرفه
Not someone who lunges from behind.
تا حالا هم کسي نتونسته حتي از شت سر
Either way, the one who survives ascends the throne.
در هر صورت ،يکي از ما  زنده  ميمونه وبه تخت ميشينه
No, Susima. The throne belongs to the one...
نه سوشيما,تاج وتخت به کسي تعلق دارد
who has the courage to sit on it.
که جرات  نشستن بر روي آن راداشته باشد.
That's a childhood trait of yours. What I want, what I like...
اين يک صفت رو دوران کودکي هم داشتي يزي رو که من ميخواستم توهم ميخواستي.
is your desire too.
تمايلاتت رو بيش از حد کردي.
You even took Grandfather's sword.
تو حتي شمشير رو هم در دوران در بزر براي خودت برداشتي
Get off the throne, Asoka.
از تخت بيا ايين , آشوک
Make me do so, Sugatra.
Sugatra ,من اين کار رو نميکنم
Not like this, Sugatra.
اين جوري نه, Sugatra نه
If you must have the throne then fight for it.
اه تاج و تخت رو ميخوايد بايد براش مبارزه کنيد
In front of everyone.
در مقابل همه
Meet me tomorrow morning and I'll fight you, before everyone.
من وتو, رو در روي هم, فردا صبح مبارزه ميکنيم
Tomorrow morning...
فردا صبح...
in front of everyone.
با احترام
Sleep well, Asoka. Tonight is your last night.
آشوک , امشب خوب بخواب ونکه آخرين شب توست
You are finished.
توبه ايان رسيدي.
I will fight him.
من با او مبارزه ميکنم .
Go ahead...fight him.
برو جلو...با اومبارزه کن .
He dared to sit on the throne today.
او جرأت کرده بر تخت بشينه.
Tomorrow, he may raise the sword on me.
فردا  هم،  ممکنه عليه من شمشيربکشه
Your Majesty, it is my belief that we analyze the situation...
اعليحضرت، من فکر ميکنم اين موضوع رو بايد مد نظر قرار بديم که
Prime Minister, my belief is that you stay silent.
نخست وزير، منم فکر ميکنم تو بايد ساکت بشي
It's you who has encouraged him. -Why blame the Prime Minister?
اين شما ييد که او را  به جاي سرزنش تشويق. -- ميکنيد؟
Asoka is under Dharma's control.
آشوک از دارما حرف شنوي داره
Stop him, Dharma. If something should happen tomorrow...
دارما , ار فردا جلوشو نيري ممنکه اتفاق بدي بيفته
the blame will be entirely yours.
عواقب آن هم ريبان ير تو هست , فقط تو
What's happening here?
اينجا ه خبره ؟
Mother is taking a vow of silence. -That will not happen here.
مادرتون روزه سکوت رفته
Everyone, leave.
همه , از ايجا بريد
What childishness is this? A vow of silence, for life?
ه به بازييه؟ روزه سکوت  ، براي زندي؟
You won't talk to me ever again.
نميخواهيد با من صحبت کنيد
Why, Mother?
را مادر؟
She won't speak to anyone.
او با هيکس نميخواد صحبت کنه
Mother says why speak when her own child turns a deaf ear?
مادر مي ويد زماني حرف ميزنه که فرزندش وش شنوا داشته باشد
Mother wants you to leave Magadha and strive to live an ordinary life...
مادرتون ميخواد شما ماادها رو ترک ويه زندي عادي داشته باشيد...
Give her your word that no one will come to know you're Prince Asoka.
طوري که هيکس اسم شاهزاده آشوک رو نشناسه
I must go? leave?
من بايد برم؟ بايد برم؟
So that others can laugh at me for running away scared?
ميخواهيد همه بخندند وبويند از مبارزه فردا ترسيد
You don't want your son to sit on the throne? But I wanted it for you.
شما نمي خواهيد فرزند تون به تخت بشينه ؟ اما من همه را براي شما ميخواستم
Here. I give in. Now speak to me.
حالا منو بشوييد ,بامن حرف ميزنيد.
Vitasoka, tell Mother to greet an ordinary man.
مادر ميويد به ويشوک بعنوان يه مرد معمولي خوش آمد ميوييم
Mother's like you, brother. She won't speak till you leave.
مادرراضي شدي، برادر. او نمي خواهد صحبت کند تا شما از اينجا نريد.
All right, I'll go.
حق باشماست من ميرم
Even if you ask, I won't return.
وتا زماني که شما نفتيد برنميردم
Speak to me.
حالا حرف بزن
Brother won't be here. He has gone, leaving Magadha.
برادر او ميخواد ماداها رو ترک کنه.
Gone? So he's scared.
رفته ؟ يعني ترسيد.
The brave Prince has fled to save his life.
شاهزاده شجاع از ترس جونش فرار کرده
Idiot. Change your tune.
ادم سفيه و احمق. اين يه مي خوني.
What's the matter with you?
موضوع يه؟
Nothing.
هيي.
Friends like us have nothing to hide.
ماهمه دوستيم نبايد يزي از هم مخفي کنيم.
Iast night, when I went home, my wife was not there.
شب که به خانه رفتم ديدم همسرم نيست.
Where did she go?
را, کجا رفته بود؟
When I asked her in the morning...
وقتي صبح ازش رسيدم...
she said she was with her friend, Kamini.
او فت که با دوستش کاميني بوده
Silly. She must have been with Kamini.
اينکه با کاميني رفيقه خوب نيست؟
You idiot, I was with Kamini.
اي احمق اخه منم با کاميني دوست هستم
No, I was with Kamini.
نه , کاميني که دوست منه
I was there too. You must have gone after me.
منکه دروغ نميم،حتما تو بعد از من باهاش دوست شدي
Strange. My wife's name is also Kamini.
قدر عجيبه ،آخه اسم زن من هم کامينيه
That dark one? -Yes.
تو مطمئني؟ -- بله.
Have you heard? Prince Asoka has gone leaving Magadha.
هي ديوانه ها خبر جديد رو شنيديد؟ شاهزاده آشوک ماادها رو ترک کرده
He must have gotten scared of Prince Susima.
حتما از سوشيم ترسيده
When Jupiter enters its twelfth position...
وقتي سياره مشتري وارد موقعيت دوازدهم بشه
every great man must go into eXile. -Really?
مردان بزر بايد تبعيد بشن.. -- واقعا؟
Iike Rama, Pandavas, Princes.
لاکي، راما ، اندواز، شاهزاده.
Strange.
عجيب و غريب.
You're not from here. Who are you?
تو مال اينطرفها نيستي ،توکي هستي
An ordinary traveler.
من ، من يه مسافر عاديم .
The sun remains the sun even behind clouds.
خورشيد، خورشيد باقي مي ماند حتي در شت ابرها.
Your destiny indicates that you are in no way ordinary.
سرنوشت شما نشان مي دهد که شما به هي وجه عادي نيستيد.
What lies in my destiny then? That I am a prince?
تو سرنوشت من ي ميبيني؟ که من شاهزاده ام؟
One day I will be enthroned? Be an emperor?
يه روز حتما به تخت ميشينم؟ امراتور ميشم؟
Even emperors are ordinary. Your destiny transcends the throne.
امراطوري هم کمه، سر نوشت شما فراتر از امراتوري وتاج وتخته.
Whose destiny can surpass that of an emperor's?
حتي سرنوشت کسي که از يش از امراتوري افتاده؟
A traveler's... when his journey has been completed.
سفرت سخته مسافر ،بايد اونو تموم کني .
Eat, child. In Kalinga no one goes to sleep hungry. You eat too.
کسي هست غذا يرش نيومده ؟ شماهم ميخوايد ؟به به ها زياد بديد
Here, Pawan. It's good food. Pawan, eat this. It's tasty.
در اينجا، Pawan اين غذاي خوبيه . Pawan، خوردن اين. خوشمزه است
Why should you eat? You too miss Mother's hand feeding you.
را بايد اينها رو بخورم؟ شما هم از دست مادر دلت نميخواد يزي بخوري؟.
No fuss. I'm an ordinary man. You an ordinary horse.
هيي نو، سرو صدا هم نکن ، من يه مرد معموليم توهم يه اسب معمولي
No royal palace or sumptuous dishes for us.
نه کاخ مجللي ونه غذاي خوبي براي ما هست
Now, it's the ground to sleep on...
در حال حاضر ،بايد روي زمين بخوابي...
the open sky above...
زير سقف آسمان...
and pretty princesses who now eXist only in our dreams.
و رنسسهاي زيبا که در حال حاضر فقط در روياهاي ما وجود دارد
Go,you searching wind, go away
برويد ، براي جستن باد ، برويد
Go seek out my beloved
برو دنبال محبوب من
One good enough for me
يکي که به اندازه کافي براي من خوبه
It cannot be...
اين نمي توانيد...
If there is...
ار... وجود ندارد
Then maybe we can be together
س شايد ما با هم مي توانيم
Go... go...
برو... برو...
The sky is a poet's page
آسمان صفحه شاعر
And I its poem
و من شعر آن
Someone like me...
کسي مثل من...
Is rare in this world
در اين جهان نادر است
Touch me not...
لمس کردن من ...
That's a dare...
جرات ميخواهد...
It would start raging fire
با اين کار دست به آتش زده
Go... go...
برو... برو...
I didn't see a thing.
من يزي نديدم.
I was just listening.
من فقط وش ميدادم.
You swim... I mean you sing very well.
شما خيلي خوب شنا ميکنيد منظورم اينه که آواز ميخونيد.
What's your name?
اسمت يه؟
I don't talk to strangers. -Stranger?
من باغريبه ها صحبت نمي کنم. -- غريبه؟
Do you not feel that we have met before?
احساس نميکنيد قبلا همدير رو ديديم؟
In some other place, in another time...
در مکان دير، در زمان ديري...
somewhere?
جايي وجود دارد؟
Who are you?
تو کي هستي؟...
Pawan (the Wind). And you?
اون ، وشما؟
Why are you following me?
را منو تعقيب ميکني؟
Your voice drew me.
صداي شما منو جلب کرد
I am warrior blood. You risk death.
من يه جنجوي خون آشامم ممکنه بميري.
I am dead.
مرده ام
My warrior.
جن جوي من.
Pawan, this place is unfit for a horse like you. Wait here.
اون اينجا براي اسبي مثل تو مکان مناسبي نيست ، بمون برمردم
Iook, another one in search of the same thing.
ناه کنيد، يکي ديه هم براي يدا کردنش از راه دوري اومده
You won't find... Nobody will.
کي رو ميخواي يدا کني ... هي کس رو يدا نميکني.
Who? -Not who, 'What'.
ه کسي؟ -- کي نه 'ه'
1 00 shining, clinking gold coins.
،100 ، سکه هاي طلا.
Reward for finding Prince Arya and Princess Kaurwaki.
اداش براي يدا کردن شاهزاده آريا و شاهزاده Kaurwaki.
You're very pretty.
تو خيلي خوشلي
And you're the prettiest, Meghna.
Meghna، .و شما زيباترين
Meghna? My name's Urvashi. -Doesn't matter, you're all pretty.
Meghna نه  Urvashi اسم من . -- مهم نيست ، همه شما خوشليد.
Who is there? Will someone dare to take up my challenge?
کسي نبود؟ آيا کسي جرات داره با من مبارزه کنه؟
Friend, you seem new here. How about you?
هي رفيق بنظرم تو جديدي ميخوام باهام دست ونجه نرم کني
Come, show us your mettle.
، قدرتت رو به ما نشون بده.
Go...go.
برو... برويد
Brave youngsters these days parade around with twigs.
جوانان شجاع اين روزها با شاخه هاي کويک رژه ميرن
Give it back. -Sit. Win it back.
اونو س بده -- بنشين.اه يروز شدي بهت سش ميدم
What's your name? -Pawan (the Wind).
اسمت يه؟ Pawan
A horse's name.
اين که اسم اسبه.
His father must be 'Badal' ( cloud).
حتما اسم درت هم بادوله'
Iook behind... There's no one.
شت سرت... کسي نبود
You won by cheating. -Either way, I won.
هي تو با تقلب بردي. -- در هر صورت، من تو رو بردم
You must fight me again. -Iet go.
تو بايد دوباره با من مبارزه کني. -- ولش کن.
I will not.
نه.
No way out. You'll have to fight.
نميزارم بري بايد با من مبارزه کني.
Where were you last night? I've been waiting for ages.
ديشب کجا بودي؟ من تا صبح منتظرت بودم
Who are all these people? Come home now, I'll show you.
اينها کي هستند؟ من نميام خونه ، بريم خونه تا نشونت بدم
You are the first to defeat Virat.
تو براي بار اوله که ويرات رو شکست ميدي.
Come with me.
با من بيا.
You've not been drinking, have you? -No.
يزي براي خوردن ، داريد؟ -- نه
You take over the bullock cart. It's dangerous to drink and ride.
بايد جشن بيريم ، با من بيا يه يزي بخوريم
He's right, let's go.
اون عاليه، س بيا بريم.
Woke up, finally? Will you just sit around? Or will you work?
بيدار شدي آخر؟ تو کارهم ميکني؟ يا فقط ميخواي بشيني؟
What work? -You must work if you want to stay.
کار ، ه کاري -- اه ميخواي اينجا بموني بايد کار کني
If not, you should leave.
ور نه بايد از اينجا بري
I can do any kind of work.
من ميتونم هر کاري رو انجام بدم تو فقط نشونم بده
This work I cannot do.
اين کارو انجام ميدم
Greetings. I'm new to this. You could face some discomfort.
سلام. من تازه به اينجا اومدم. .اه ناراحت نميشيد منو کمک کنيد مشکلم حل بشه
Even so, please don't move. And please don't kick.
حالا، لطفا اصلا حرکت نکنيد. و لطفا  وا هم نزنيد.
Your eyes too are beautiful.
شمهاي شما بيش از حد زيبا هستند  .
You? Why are you following me?
شما؟را همش دنبال من هستي؟
I am following you?
من به دنبال شما؟
Yesterday I was in the forest and you emerged from the waterfalls.
من ديروز توي جنل بودم که شما از طرف آبشار نازل شديد
Now you're here on the preteXt of getting milk.
در حال حاضر شما به بهانه رفتن شير اومدي سراغم.
And what were you doing in my dream last night?
واينکه ، از فکر ديدن من شب و روز نداري؟
At least tell me your name.
حداقل اسمت رو به من بو.
Give me the milk. -Iook, over there.
شير رو بده به من. --ناه کنيد آنجاست.
Hey, Warrior.
هي ، جنجو.
Stop. Princess Kaurwaki.
هي وايسا ، شاهزاده کروواکي
Yes, we found her. The 1 00 gold coins are ours.
ناه کنيد ، خودشه ، شاهزاده کروواکي ،100 سکه طلا مال ما ميشه
1 00 gold coins for her?
100 سکه طلا براي او؟
Back off. She is ours. -Know how to swim?
هي از اينجا برو . او مال ما است. -- تو شنا بلدي ؟
Yes, of course.
بله ، البته
And you? That's good.
و شما؟ خوبه.
Iets go.
بريم ، زود از اينجا بريم.
You crazy? lf you can't swim then why jump into the water?
ديونه شدي؟تو که شنا بلد نيستي را ريدي توي آب؟
What's wrong? Seems all of Kalinga is after you...
ي شده؟به نظر مي رسه همه دنبالتون هستند
Princess Kaurwaki.
شاهزاده کارواکي کيه ؟
You're among them. For you, all I mean is 1 00 gold coins.
تو هم با اونهايي منو براي سکه ميخواي.
I couldn't put a price on you.
من نميتونم بر روي شما قيمت بزارم.
The earth doesn't have enough gold for that.
زمين به اندازه کافي براي خريدنت طلا نداره.
Stay with Arya. He is alone. Stop. Who sent you?
تو مواظب اين باش ، من ميرم سراغ بقيه. صبر کنيد. کي شما رو فرستاده ؟
Drink up.
بخور .
When I'm king, there will be food for all.
وقتي که من  ادشاه شدم غذا براي همه وجود خواهد داشت.
Don't tell anyone.
ساکت يکي داره مياد
Who is this? ls he dead? -It's just an injury. Go back inside.
ه کسي حاضر است؟ LS اين کيه؟ اون مرده؟ نه فقط يه جراحت ساده است تو برو داخل --
How did he get hurt? -Bheema hit him. Go inside.
طوري صدمه ديده؟ بهيم اونو زده تو برو داخل.
Did he come to kill me?
اومده منو بکشه؟
Arya, go inside.
آريا، برو داخل
Why did you bring him here? You know it's dangerous.
را اونو به اينجا آوردي؟ تو مي دانيد که خطرناکه
Why did you hit him? -Arya, go inside.
را اونو زدي؟ -- آريا، برو داخل.
First tell me, why you hit him.
اول به من بورا اونو زدي.
Why did you bring him here?
براي ي اونو به اينجا آورديد؟
He could be anyone, a murderer, an assassin...
اونوميشناسي ، قاتل، قاتل
He saved my life, Bheema. -Don't you know why?
اون زندي منو نجات داد ،بهيم. -- ميدوني  را؟
He's after the same thing: 1 00 gold coins.
اون دنبال 100سکه  طلاست.
You may take your life lightly but Arya is my responsibility.
شايد براي شما مهم نباشه امامن درقبال آريا مسئوليت دارم .
Arya is my brother, General. -Iet's go then.
آريا برادر منه، س بيا از اين جا بريم.
I can't leave him in this condition. -You'll have to.
من نمي تونم اونو تواين وضعيت تنها بزارم. -- شما بمونيد.
We are leaving from here. -General, are you ordering me?
ما از اينجا مي رويم. --  ، ميخواييد منو اينجا تنها بزاريد؟
No. I'm just trying to make you understand.
نه ، من فقط دارم تلاش ميکنم تاشما موضوع روبهتر درک کنيد
The rest is up to you.
بقيه اش با خودتونه.
Forgive me, Prince. Please have your meal now.
مرا ببخش، رنس. لطفا غذا تون رو ميل کنيد
Here, I'm Prince? lnside you scold me?
در اينجا ، من شاهزاده هستم؟ شما را دستور ميديد وسرم داد ميزنيد؟
Scold me then after eating. -I don't wish to eat.
اوقات تلخي کردن من براي اينه که شما غذا نميخوريد. -- من نميخوام تنها غذا بخورم.
I want to go home -Yes, Prince. We leave tomorrow.
من مي خواهم به خانه بروم -- بله ، شاهزاده. فردا از اينجا ميريم.
Not tomorrow, today. -I said tomorrow.
فردا نه، امروز. -- من فتم فردا.
It's always tomorrow.
فردا، فردا  ،هميشه فردا
When I am king everything will be settled today.
وقتي که من  ادشاه بشم همه يز رو امروز حل و فصل ميکنم .
No tomorrows.
نه فردا.
Kaurwaki...
Kaurwaki...
Kaurwaki, give it to me.
اونو بده به من ، کارواکي.
Mother, look at Kaurwaki.
مادر ببين ، کاروواکي.
Mother.
مادر
It's all right. It was only a nightmare.
يزي نيست. اين فقط يک کابوس است.
I want to go home. -Yes. We will go.
من مي خواهم به خانه بروم. -- بله. حتما ميريم.
Where is Prince Arya?
شاهزاده آريا کجاست؟
I assure the senate that Prince Arya will soon be with us...
من سنا اطمينان مي دهم که شاهزاده آريا به زودي مياد...
to take the royal place of his late father.
ومن اون به جاي در مرحومش بر تخت سلطنت مينشانم .
I have announced a 1 00 gold coin reward to anyone who finds him.
من اعلام کردام که 100 سکه  طلا اداش به کسي ميدم که اونو يدا کنه.
It's not just a matter of finding Prince Arya.
تنها مشکل ما يدا کردن شاهزاده نيست .
The King's assassins roam free.
کساني که شاه رو ترور کردن هم دارن آزاد ميردند..
What's happening in Kalinga? Answer me.
توي كاليناه ه خبره ؟
There is a conspiracy brewing in Kalinga.
بوي توطعه توي كاليناه مياد .
The person involved is here in this senate amongst us.
كسي كه داره اين توطعه رو فرماندهي ميكنه همينجا داخل مجلس سنا هست.
Who is he? -You.
اون كيه ؟ -- شما.
Or you. It may even be you. -Me?
يا شما.يا حتي ممكنه شما باشيد. -- من؟
It could be anyone.
يا هر كسي كه اينجاست.
Suspecting each other is futile.
شك ما به همديه بي فايده است.
It's your responsibility to find the culprit, Prime Minister.
شما مسوليت يدا كردن مجرم را داريد، نخست وزير
We trust you.
ما به شما اعتماد كامل داريم.
Kaurwaki...
Kaurwaki...
Now Kaurwaki? last night another name was on your lips.
ديشب تا حالا اسم كارواكي روي لباته ، تو اسم ديه اي بلد نيستي ؟
Is that so?
اينطوريه؟
And what were you doing so close to me last night?
وديشب هم همين قدر به من نزديك بوديد؟
Don't go. It still hurts...
نرو. هنوز درد دارم...
If you leave, the pain will get worse.
اه بري دردم بيشترميشه .
My Warrior, listen. -I don't want to hear.
هي جنجو، وش كن. -- نميخوام وش كنم.
But I want to say it. -Fine. Say it.
اما من مي خواهم بم خوشله. -- باشه  بو.
Can I come close and say it? -What are you doing?
ميشه نزديكتر بيام و بم؟ -- ه کار مي کنيد؟
Nothing? -I saw him trying to tell you something.
هي ي؟ -- ولي من ديدم ، ميخواست يه يزي به تو به.
He was telling me a story. -I want to hear it too.
ميخواست برام قصه به. -- قصه ، من ميخوام بشنوم
But I don't know any stories. -I order you. Tell me a story.
اما من هر داستاني رو نمي دونم. -- به شما دستور ميدم يه داستان برام بي.
Prince, don't get angry. I will tell you a story.
شاهزاده، لطفا عصبي نشيد من برايتان. يه داستان تعريف ميكنم.
Once, there was a prince. -Iike me?
يه بار ، يه شاهزاده اي بود-- مثل من؟
A little older. He left his kingdom and roamed the jungle.
کمي مسن تر. او ادشاهي رو ترك كرد وبه جنل ناه برد.
Iike us? Then what? -One day he heard something...
ما؟ س ه؟ -- يک روز، او يه صدايي شنيد...
Someone was singing. The voice drew him to a waterfall.
يكي داشت آواز ميخوند. صدا ازطرف آبشارميومد ونظر اونو به خودش جلب كرد.
He saw a princess, bathing...
شاهزاده خانمي، در حال حمام كردن بود
Her lovely body, head to toe, glistening with water drops.
بدن دوست داشتني او ، سر تا ا، درخشان با قطرات آب.
And the prince fell in love.
و شاهزاده عاشقش شد.
At first sight. -I knew it. Then?
در ناه اول. -- من اينو ميدونستم.بعدش ي شد؟
Said the prince to the princess, ''You sing beautifully!''
شاهزاده به شاهزاده خانم فت ،، ''شما صداي خيلي خوبي داريد!
The princess got angry, picked up her sword.
شاهزاده خانم هم عصباني شد و، شمشير خود را برداشت.
Why? The prince didn't do anything.
را؟شاهزاده كه کاري نكرده.
He watched her bathe, you see. -So? I too bathe in the open.
ونكه موقع حمام كردن اونو ديد.. --منم موقع حمام در رو باز ميزارم
You're different. The Princess had no clothes on her.
شما فرق ميكنيد. شاهزاده خانم کاملا" لخت بود.
Arya, supper's ready. Come eat. -But I want to hear the story.
آريا، شام آماده است. بيا بخور. -- اما من مي خواهم بقيه داستان رو بشنوم.
First eat. Then the story.
اول غذا. بعد داستان.
How are you now? -I'm fine.
حالتون طوره؟ -- من خوبم.
I must find the rascal who hit me from behind.
من بايد خيلي  ست باشم كه منو از شت زدي.
This rascal. He hits everybody.
اين سته. او با همه اين كارو ميكنه.
We should leave now. - By the way, where are you headed?
ما بايد اينجا رو ترك كنيم. -- بذريم، شما كجا ميريد؟
Kalinga.
Kalinga.
That's where I am going too.
اتفاقا منم مسيرم همون جاست.
We won't trouble you. Iet's go.
شما بريد ما مزاحمتون نميشيم.
Tell me the story.
براي من قصه بو.
Rascal.
حقه بازي.
What is this?
اين يه؟
Ieft your work without warning?
کجا بدون اجازه رفتي؟
Work when you please. Ieave when you please. This won't do.
من بهت لطف کردم. من بهت لطف کردم ولي تو کارت رو انجام ندادي ومعلوم نيست کجارفتي.
She went away. She didn't even look back.
او رفت. بدون حتي يک ناه.
Is it done?
حلا يکار کنم؟ بو؟
Come, get ready.
بيا، آماده دريافت است.
Iet's catch the evening boat. Iet's get on it. Come, let's go.
قايق آماده رفتنه.. بياييد وبرروي آن سوار شيد. بياييد، امشب اجازه سواري داريد
There will be an anchor, somewhere...
لنر رو بندازيد، ......
Somewhere there's a shore... Iet's go. Iet's go.
جايي که ساحل وجود دارد... برويد.  زود باشيد بياييد.عجله کنيد .عجله کنيد..
Prepare yourself, then let's leave
آماده باشيد، وقتي سوارقايق ميشيد
Whether we swim or we sink... We have to get across
اين با شماست که شنا کردن رابدانيد والا غرق ميشيد
The evening will be so pleasant
غروب دلذيرخواهد شد تا
The words will be mine. But the thought yours
حرفهاي زشت دلذير ميشوند. اما فکرهاي شما
The talk will be innocent... sweet, diluted with honey
بحث هاي وناهاني که ميکنيد مانند شهد و عسل شيرين  خواهد شد
What is this surge of love? Do I drown to eXperience it?
اين موجي که از عشق آمده يست؟ يعني دارم توي آن غرق ميشوم؟
Can't you tell what it is? Where could it lead?
آيا مي توانيد بوييد آن يست؟ از کجا شروع شده؟
The heart will burn, the eyes will fill
قلبم را خواهد سوزاند، .
You fight very well.
س ميخواي مبارزه کني، خوبه.
Here, straighten this.
بير،حالا تو صافش کن.
I'll be leaving too. -Wait.
.من اين کار رو نميکنم. -- صبر کن
The fight is not over. -I warn you.
مبارزه تمام نشده . -- من بهت هشدار مي دم.
I have learnt the art of battle from the great teXts.
من هنر مبارزه کردن رو از کتب بزر آموخته ام
I know 1 8 tactics of fighting.
من 18 حرکت مهم جني رو بلدم.
I do too.
من بيشتر ازاينها بلم.
All 1 8? -All 1 8 of them. Come, fight.
18 حرکت رو؟ -- بله همه 18 حرکت رو بياجلو.
Tell me, friend. Do you know the 1 9th tactic?
بو ببينم ، حرکت 19 رو هم بلدي؟
Which is this 1 9th tactic?
حرکت 19؟
The 1 9th tactic?
آره حرکت 19
In the 1 9th tactic the warrior fights his foe blindfolded.
در اين تاکتيک هردو بايد باشمهاي بسته مبارزه کنند.
Iike this.
حالا.
Pawan, Pawan.
اون, اون.
Quiet, everyone.
همه ، ساکت.
What's new in that? Even I know this tactic.
ي فکر کردي؟ خودم بلدم .
Prepare yourself.
آماده باش.
Have you got the blindfold on? -Yes.
شماتو بستي؟ -- بله.
You can't see anything? -Not a thing.
يزي نميبيني؟ -- نه هي يز.
You hit first.
شروع کن.
Try again.
دوباره سعي کن.
Keep at it.
مواظب باش.
Friend, remember... the '1 9th' tactic.
هي رفيق ، تاکتيک 19 رو هيوقت فراموش نکن
Quiet.
خفه شيد.
Will he be back?
يعني بر ميرده؟
Who, Pawan?
کي  ، اون
Yes, Pawan. I want to hear the story.
بله ، اون ميخوام برام قصه به.
Here you go, prince. Eat some fruit.
بفرما، رنس. کمي ميوه بخوريد.
Bheema, know any stories?
بهيم ، تو هم قصه بلدي؟
No.
نه.
No for everything.
نه ، همش نه.
Tell us, who are you? What are you doing here?
بو توکي هستي؟ ه کار مي کنيد؟
Princess, hide.
شاهزاده خانم ، مخفي شويد.
Were you looking for me?
دنبال من ميردي؟
When you left you did not look back even once.
نميتونم ناهت رو فراموش کنم.
Take care of Arya.
آريا مراقب باش.
Don't leave them, Bheema.
از اون طرف رفت ، بهيم.
He will kill everyone.
همه رو بکشيد.
Well, what's this? The sun pendant.
خب ، اين يه؟ آويز خورشيد.
It is our Prince Arya, isn't it?
اين شاهزاده آريا ما است ، نه؟
Iook, our Prince got scared.
نه کنيد ، شاهزاده ما ترسيده.
Don't be afraid, Prince. We won't do anything to hurt you.
ترسيديد ، رنس ؟يزي نيست نميزارم زياد اذيت بشيد .
You fight well. Where did you learn?
خوب ميجنيد. کجا  ياد رفتيد؟
I'm a soldier in the Magadha army.
من يه سرباز در ارتش ماادها بودم.
You, soldier of Magadha army?
سرباز ماادها،
And I'm the General of Kalinga. That makes us enemies.
منم سرباز کاليناه هستم ، ماباهم دشمنيم.
Enemies.
دشمن.
How long? How much longer will it take?
ه مدت؟ قدر ديرطول خواهد کشيد؟
Do I have to wait for eternity to ascend the throne?
ي فکر ميکني ، تا ابد بايد براي به تخت نشستن صبر کنم؟؟
Find Prince Arya and kill him.
هره زودتر شاهزاده آريا رو يدا کنيد واون رو بکشيد.
As proof, hand me the sun pendant he wears around his neck.
تا روز يکشنبه بيشتر وقت نداريد، من بايد يراق ادشاهي رو ردنم بيندازم.
Go.
برو.
Why a sword in such beautiful hands?
را شمشير توي دستان زيباي شماست؟
I want to be as skilled as you in wielding the sword.
ميخوام مثل تو ماهر بشم وحق اونها رو کف دستشان بذارم
To fight the evil ones. -Who are they?
براي مبارزه با آنهايي که بد هستند. -- اونها کي هستند ؟
The ones who killed my parents.
آنها در ومادم رو کشتند.
I'm with you, Kaurwaki. I will always be close to you.
من باتو هستم ،کرواکي، من هميشه درکنارت ميمونم.
I don't want to depend on others.
اين موضوع به کس ديه اي مربوط نيست.
Then, hold the sword like this.
س ، شمشيرتون رو اينطوري نهداريد.
Iet it be a part of your body. Iet it connect to your soul.
حالا خوتو بهش بسار،تن و روحت را به شمشير بسار. .وباهاش ارتباط برقرار کن
No fear, no hesitation... No sense of life or death.
بدون ترس ، بدون درن... هي حس زندي يا مر.
Focus only on your target.
تنها روي هدفت تمرکز کن.
Not like this.
ديه هي وقت،.
Never shift your eyes from your enemy.
هرز شم خود را از دشمن دشمن برندار.
I just touched my warrior and she took offense.
من فقط به جنجو دست زدم ،جرم که نيست.
Just imagine, she pushed me.
تصور کن، او منو هول داد.
You men. You could not have said or heard anything.
شما مردان.  نمي توانيد يزي رو که مييد ،بشنويد
Probably grabbed the girl's hand. -I did. So?
با اون خشن بر خورد کردي؟
You need to be gentle with girls. Some love, some flowers...
دختران نياز به ملايمت دارن. بعضي وقتها با عشق ، بعضي وقتها با ل...
say some words of love.
بعضي وقتها واژه ها از عشق مين.
Say what? love speaks for itself.
بو : ه؟ براي عشق خودت ببرشون.
Are you afraid of eXpressing love? -I'm not afraid of anything.
يه ، از ابراز عشق ميترسي؟ -- نه، من از يزي نميترسم
Nonsense. Tell me, how does one go about this love talk?
مزخرف نو. به من بو، ونه بم عاشقشم؟
Here. Hold these flowers. Take it all.
اين لها رو بير،و.
Go tell her... I love you...you alone.
بهش بو... من تو رو دوست دارم... تنها تورو.
I can't think of anything but you.
نميتونم بجز تو به يز ديه اي فکر کنم.
After meeting you my world has changed.
بعد از ملاقات باتو دنياي من عوض شده.
I have changed.
من تغيير کردم.
I can't understand anything. If I keep silent, I'll go mad.
من ديه نميتونم يزي رو درک کنم وبه کلي ديونه شدم. .
All that? I can't do it.
ي فتي؟ من نمي تونم بم.
Hold this? You have to say it.
تو ميتوني؟ بيا اينها رو بير وامتحان كن.
I'm ln love with you -Right.
من عاشقتم. -- درسته..
Only you. -Perfect.
فقط شما. -- کاملا درسته
Keep at it and I'll get some more flowers.
تو همه رو درست فتي، لها رو نهدار براي خودت وتمرين كن.
Ever since I have met you, everything's changed.
از زماني که من شما رديدم، همه يز تغيير کرده .
I have changed, you seem changed.
من تغيير کردم، توهم تعغير كردي.
I can't think of anything or anyone else but you...
نميتونم بغيراز تو به يز ديري فكر كنم...
You.
تو.
Your love story brings tears to my eyes.
داستان عشقت روكه شنيدم اشك هام سرازير شد.
Now your tears will flow.
حالا من اشكت رو در ميارم..
My friend, not today. Somebody is waiting.
نه دوست من ، امروز قرار مهمي دارم.
They'll have to wait a lifetime.
اونها بايد يه عمر صبر کنن.
Virat, my friend... -Nothing will work today.
ببين دوست عزيز ، من،... -- هيي نو.
No blindfold, no 1 9th tactic. Today nothing will work.
نه شمهاي بسته ، نه تاکتيک 19. هي ي امروز به كمكت نمياد.
What if I say there's someone behind you?
اه بم زنت شت سرته ي؟
I won't look back.
من ناه نميكنم.
There's someone behind you. -I know there's no one.
زنت شت سرته. -- كسي شت سرم نيست.
Virat, somebody is there.
ويرات، يكي شت سرته.
You're cheating again. Telling me lies?
ميخواي تقلب كني. يكي شت سرت قايم شده؟
I'm leaving, my friend.
من كه بهت فتم ، دوست عزيز.
So? You promised you'll be with me forever.
س تو الكي فتي منو دوست داري ،ها ؟.
After that day, I see you today.
حالا مي فهمم.
I won't speak to him ever, didn't even tell me before he left.
اصلا باهاش حرف نميزنم ،حتي اه تركم كنه.
Are you crying?
داري ريه ميكني؟
First, you fight with Pawan. Then you sit here and cry?
اون ، توي مبارزه همه رو شکست داد و اول شد اونوقت تو اينجا نشستي و ريه ميکني ؟
Why should I cry?
ريه نميکنم
What have I to do with him? -Iook, Pawan's horse.
من که با او کاري ندارم .
You glass doll...
عروسک شيشه اي...
Sealed in your lips is the lilt of love
يزي که روي لبت مهر و موم کردي آهن عشقه
But you won't speak
اما تو يزي نميي
Or utter it
مطلقا
It lingers on your eyelashes
بر روي مژه هاي خود را lingers
And lurks on lowered eyes
توي شمات کم کن و
Come, listen.
بيا، وش کن.
Sweeter than sugar
شيرين تر از قند
are your veiled eyelids
لک محجبه خود را
You don't open your eyes
از روي شمات بردار
or reveal what they say
تا يدا بشن اون شمها
If you wish to cross the hills I'll move mountains for you
اه تو ميخواي از ته عبور کني من حاضرم کوه ها را براي تو جابجا کنم
If you seek shelter in the clouds I'll ward off the monsoon rains
اه از باران بدنبال سر ناهي من ابر ها رو جابجا ميکنم تا باران بند بياد
A bird in the sky will guide you to the hill where the sun rises
رنده اي در آسمان شما را راهنمايي ميکنه که شت ته ها به طلوع خورشيد برسي
Please introduce yourself, beautiful Your smile is sweetness
لطفا خودتان را معرفي کنيد، با اون لبخند شيرني که داريد
You are a foreigner, will forget me easily. Give me your promise
شما يک غريبه ايد، که وعده هاتون رو براحتي فراموش ميکنيد
So I can wear it like a jewel
بنابراين من مي توانم آن را مانند يک جواهر بر تن کنم
The prime minister of Magadha has sent a message.
يه يام از طرف نخست وزير مادها دارم.
Please continue with the story.
بقيه قصه رو بو.
The story... where were we?
داستان... بيا اينجا بشين
The Princess's clothes...
لباس شاهزاده...
She wore them, walked away, and the prince followed her
او بهش لباس داد و به راه دوري رفت
Why?
را؟
Iovely princess, alone in a dark forest...
شاهزاده خانم، تنها در يک جنل تاريک...
What of wild animals?
ميون حيوانات وحشي
Any wild animal seeing a lovely princess would follow.
همه حيوانات وحشي ميخواستند شاهزاده خانم رو دنبال کنند.
Then what happened?
س ه اتفاقي افتاد؟
The princess turned around and said, ''l am a princess...
شاهزاده خانم برشت و فت : من يک شاهزاده خانم هستم...
If you follow me you will get a tight slap''.
اه بازهم دنبالم بياييد "سيلي محکم دريافت ميکنيد
The prince left then?
را مه کار بدي کرده بود
No, he was shameless.
نه ، او بي شرمانه عمل کرد.
Is this your story or mine? You tell it then.
تو داستان ميي يامن ؟ اه بلدي بيا خودت بقيه اش رو بو
No, you tell it.
نه ، خودت بو.
Why would our prince who braved death bother over a slap?
شاه زاده فت را ميزني من که نجاتت دادم؟
He kept following the princess. Suddenly, three monsters appeared.
او شاهزاده خانم رو رها کرد، ناهان سه تا هيولا ظاهر شدند. .
Where was the prince from?
شاهزاده  کجا بود؟
The prince had no kingdom. It was stolen from him.
شاهزاده رفته بود ،تا ادشاهي که ازش رفته بودند رو س بيره .
Just like us.
ما اينجوري هستيم.
Someone stole our land as well.
يکي کشورمون رو به سرقت برده
Someone stole our Kalinga.
کاليناه ما رو به سرقت بردند.
So what?
س ه؟
The sun is yours, the moon too. All the stars up there are yours.
خورشيد مال شما است، ماه هم مال توست. تمام ستاره ها هم مال شما.
No one can take that away from you.
هي کس نمي تواند آنها رو از شما بيره.
Really? -Yes.
واقعا؟ -- بله..
What's more, no man can take your land away from you.
بيشتر ه ، هي مردي نمي تواند زمين خود را بدون وجود شما درو کند.
I'm there with you. I'll get your land back for you.
من و تو به اونجا ميريم و همه زمينها رو س مييريم
Hey, warrior.
هي ، جنجو.
I ... Iisten to me.
وش كن به من.
I have not told anyone this before. Kaurwaki...listen.
ميخواهم حرفهايي که توي دلمه رو بهت بم.
Please listen.
لطفا وش کن.
Tell me.
وش ميکنم بو.
Kaurwaki, I love you, only you.
Kaurwaki، من عاشقت شدم
I can't think of anything or anyone but you.
نميتونم به هي کس و هي يز فکر کنم بغير از شما.
Ever since I have met you everything has changed.
از لحظه اي که ديدمت همه يزم تغير کرده.
I have changed.
من تغيير کرده ام.
I don't know what to do.
من نمي دونم ه بايد بکنم.
If I didn't tell you, I would lose my mind.
اه نم ممکنه ديونه بشم
I love you, only you.
من شما را دوست دارم، فقط شما.
I can't think of anything or anyone else but you.
من نميتونم به هي يز بغير از تو فکر کنم .
Ever since I have met you everything has changed.
از زماني که من شما را ملاقات کردم همه يز تغيير کرده است.
I have changed.
من تغيير کردم.
I'm glad you told me.
خوشحالم که همه يز رو فتي.
If you didn't, I would lose my mind.
ااه نميفتي ، من ديونه ميشدم
That's eXactly what I said.
اينها دقيقا همان يزي است ميخواستم بم
But you should say it like this.
آره ولي من فتم.
Where were you?
کجا بودي؟
With Pawan.
با اون بودم.
What were you doing?
يکار ميکرديد؟
Is this the way to behave? That too with an ordinary soldier?
فکر ميکنيد شايسته شما هست ؟؟ که بيش از حد به يک سرباز عادي دل ببنديد
Bheema, don't forget who it is you are talking to.
بهيم ، جاياه خودت رو فراموش نکن فکر کن رو برويت کي نشسته.
That's why I am speaking out.
به همين دليله که ميخوام بم.
It is not right for you to associate with Pawan.
اين براي شما مناسب  نيست معاشرت با، اون.
Careful, Bheema. I love Pawan.
مراقب حرف زدنت باش بهيم ، من عاشق اون هسشتم.
You love Pawan?
شما عاشق اون هستيد؟
Who is Pawan? Where does he come from?
شما اون رو ميشناسيد ميدونيد از کجا آمده؟
He says four nice words to you and you think it's love?
هار تا کلمه قشن فت وتو فکر کردي عاشقته؟
How do you see it? You think I don't know what love is?
تو ي فکر کردي ؟ که من نميدونم عشق يه؟
You don't.
نه که نميدوني.
You don't know the difference between love and a commoner's lust.
تو تفاوت بين عشق و شهوت اشرافي رو نميدوني
Don't forget that you are just a General...
فراموش نکن که تو يک رايتي
and I'm a princess.
و من يک شاهزاده خانم
You are my servant. A slave to my royal family.
دستم رو ول کن تو يه خدمت کاري
Yes, I'm a servant. But who are you?
بله ، من يه خدمت کارم اما تو کي هستي؟
You think you are a princess? The family you are so proud of...
تو فکر ميکني يه شاهزاده اي؟ وصاحب يه خوانواده ر افتخار
What did you say?
ه فتيد؟
What about my family? Tell me, Bheema.
در مورد خانوادم ه ميدوني ، بهيم؟ هره ميدوني بو.
You were found by a fisherman. Your origin is unknown.
توسط ماهي يرها آوردنت ، از کجا آمده بودي رو کسي نميدونه
No one knows your lineage...
هي کس نمي داند اصل و نسبت يه...
The king adopted you.
ادشاه تو را به فرزندي رفت
Who am I then?
س من کيم؟
Nobody knows.
هي کس نمي داند.
My warrior, why are you here alone?
جنجوي من، را تنهايي به اينجا آمدي؟
I know what you are thinking.
ميدونم داري به ي فکر ميکني
Me, a princess. He, a mere soldier.
من يه شاهزاده نيستم ، فقط يه سرباز صفرم.
Arriving with his heart, horse and sword.
وبا قلب و شمشيرم اومدم جلو
Warrior. What happened? What's wrong?
جنجو. ه اتفاقي افتاده؟ ي شده؟
I am no warrior, Pawan.
اون ، من شاهزاده خانم نيستم
Those who I thought were my parents...
کساني که من فکرميکردم در و مادرم هستند...
I am not of their blood.
من از خون آنها نيستم.
They found me, Pawan. They raised me as an orphan.
دل آنها براي من سوخته ، اون ومنو به فرزندي قبول کردند
I have no identity, Pawan.
من يه بي هويتم ، اون
What difference is there...
ه فرقي ميکنه...
between the blood of a warrior and that of an ordinary man?
ه فرقي بين خون تو ويک شاهزاده هست؟
Nothing's changed. I love you.
هي يز تعغير نکرده ، من تو رو دوست دارم.
Who do you love? Who am l?
کي رو دوست داري ؟ من کي هستم؟
You are my warrior, my princess.
تو شاهزاده مني ، رنسس من.
Come with me.
با من بيا.
Iook. Iook at the flame.
Iook. Iook در شعله.
Are you going to push me away again?
دوباره ميخواي منو هل بدي؟
Not so quick. Tell me, what's my wedding gift?
شاهزاده به همين سادي قبول نميکنه ، بو ببينم ه هديهاي آوردي
I've given you my heart. What more?
من قلبم رو بهت هديه دادم، ازاين بيشتر ي هست؟
Your horse.
اسب شما.
He's yours.
او متعلق به شماست.
Your sword. -That too.
شمشيرت رو. -- اونهم به تو تعلق داره.
Your clothes.
لباس هايت.
Not in front of the horse.
اينو ديه نه شاهزاده.
What are you doing? My Warrior...no...no...
ه کار مي کنيد؟ شاهزاده من... نه... نه...
I'll be right back.
شما همين جا باشيد برميردم.
Stand upright, don't bow.
کار ميکني بايست، تعظيم نکن.
Greetings, Prince Asoka.
سلام ، شاهزاده آشوک
Embrace me.
بيا تو بغلم.
Why are you here?
براي ي اومدي اينجا؟
Your mother wants to meet you.
مادرتون مي خواد شما رو ببينه.
Tell Mother I will not return.
به مادرم بيد من بر نميردم
She is very ill.
اون سخت بيماره.
You may go.
خيلي خوب ، تو برو
What's the matter?
ي شده؟
Mother's unwell.
مادرم ناخوشه.
You should go to her then.
تو بايد بري اونو ببيني.
What about you and Arya?
در مورد شما و آريا ه؟
We'll be fine. We'll stay here till you get back.
يزي نيست ، ما همين جاميمانيم تا شما بررديد
Please go.
لطفا برويد
You're leaving again? I won't let you go.
ميخواي دوباره بري ؟ من نميزارم بري.
Prince Arya, a matter of two days. I'll return soon.
رنس آريا ،من به شما قول ميدم زود برم وبرردم
You did not even finish the story. -Where were we?
تو هنوز آخر داستان رو نفتي. -- او داستان، کجا بوديم؟
Yes... the three monsters died.
کجا ...ها ، سه هيولا رو کشت
The prince killed them all.
شاهزاده همه آنها رو کشت
The Princess's anger turned to love.
خشم شاهزاده خانم تبديل به عشق شد
The prince asked for her hand in marriage.
شاهزاده از او درخواست ازدواج کرد.
She said yes, right?
او فت : بله ، درسته؟
Instantly.
فورا.
Then?
وبعد؟
Then the prince left.
بعد شاهزاده اونو ترک کرد
Where to?
به کجا؟
To his mother who was ill.
براي ديدن مادر مريضش،آخه اون مادرش رو خيلي دوست داشت.
This is a sad story.
اين يه داستان غم انيزه.
No way. The prince will return with hundreds of horses and elephants...
نه اصلا هم غم انيز نيست ونکه شاهزاده با صدها اسب و فيل بر ميرده...
...to take his princess away.
... وهمه دور شاهزاده خانم جمع ميشن
Tell the prince to return soon. His princess will be waiting.
به شاهزاده بيد زود بررده. آخه شاهزاده خانم خيلي دلتنش ميشه.
The prince will come back with hundreds of horses and elephants.
شاهزاده بر ميرده با صدها نفر از اسب ها و فيل ها.
You take care of Kaurwaki.
شما مراقب کرو واکي باشيد ، رنس
Greetings, Prince.
سلام، رنس.
Where is Mother? -Come inside.
مادرم کجاست؟ -- بفرماييد داخل.
You lie to me and then want God's forgiveness?
شما به من دروغ فتيد ،فکر ميکنيد خدا شما رو خواهد بخشيد؟
Had I not lied how would I see my son?
اه دروغ نميفتم ، طور ميتونستم تورو ببينم؟
Seen me? Now I must leave. Someone is waiting for me.
منو ديديد ؟حالا ديه بايد برم ، کسي هست که منتظر منه
Who?
ه کسي؟
Someone.
يه کسي.
As lovely as a lotus, a heavenly creature.
يه موجود دوست داشتني ، مثل يه نيلوفر آبي
She is so beautiful. Anyone who sees her...
او به قدري زيبا است. که هر کي ببينتش
Will become a poet?
به يک شاعر تبديل ميشه؟
No... a lover.
خير.. به يک عاشق.
You forget the white hair.
موي سفيد را فراموش کرده ايد.
White hair?
کدام موي سفيد؟
She is someone else but you'll always be my first love.
اون يار منه ،ولي شما عشق اول وآخر من هستي و ميماني
Mere words. Who is she?
نميخواد با اين حرفات منو ول بزني. اون کيه؟
Kaurwaki. -Kaurwaki? What of her family?
کرواکي کروواکي؟خانواده اش کجاست؟
All here. You, Vitasoka, me. We are her family.
همين جا .شما،ويتاشوک ومن.همه ما  خانواده اش هستيم
Mother, I have married her. -Married?
مادر ، من حالا متاهل شدم. -- متاهل؟
Why didn't you bring her? -Not like this.
را اونو به اينجا نياوردي؟ --  اين طوري که نميشه مادر .
When I do, Magadha will welcome her ceremoniously.
وقتي اونو به اينجا ميارم ،همه ماادها بايد به اون خوش آمد بن
The streets will be lit with lamps, decorated with flowers.
خيابانها بايد بال و لامها ي روشن و زيبا تزيين بشن
Then I will tell her who I am. -You've not told her yet?
اونوقته که بهش ميم من کي هستم. -- تو بهش نفتي کي هستي؟
I told a lovely white-haired lady that I won't tell anyone.
نه ،خانومي با موهاي سفيد ودوست داشتني فت ،به هرکسي نو کي هستي
Silly.
ديوانه.
Take the blessings of the King.
يه سري به ادشاه بزن
Praise the lord.
خدارو شکر،خدا رو شکر.
General, the rumor all over Kalinga is that Prince Arya has been killed.
توي کالين شايعه شده بود که شاهزاده آريا رو کشتند
The senate has decided to place someone else on the throne.
مجلس سنا تصميم رفته که شخص دير ي رو جايزين شما کنه.
I know that's why it's important that I go to Kalinga.
مي دانم، من به کالين ميرم ببينم ه خبره
It's unsafe for Arya to go there now.
درحال حاضر آنجا براي شاهزاده آريا نا امنه
Princess, give me your anklet...
شاهزاده خانم، لطفا اون دستبند رو بديد...
Arya, your necklace.
آريا ، لطفا ردن بندت رو باز کن.
No one should know they are hiding here.
هي کس نبايد بفهمه که آنها اينجا نهان شدند
Don't worry, General. I will guard them with my life.
نران نباشيد ژنرال، من با جان و دل ازايشون نهداري ميکنم
He's served the royal family for years. You'll be safe here.
اون ند سال  به خانواده سلطنتي خدمت کرده شما اينجا درامانيد
Don't go anywhere until my return.
همين جا بمانيد تا من برردم
Yes... now I have to listen to the General's orders.
بله...در حال حاضر من بايد به دستورات يه خدمتکار وش کنم
Greetings, Susima.
سلام ، سوشم
Greetings.
سلام.
Where were you all these days?
اين روزها کجا بوديد؟
Just wandering around.
همين اطراف رسه ميزدم
Tomorrow morning, in front of everyone.
فردا صبح، در مقابل همه، مبارزه ميکنيم
I was just scaring you. I don't want to fight.
شوخي کردم. من نمي خواهم باتو مبارزه کنم.
Susima, I don't want the throne or the crown.
سوشم من نه شاهزادي رو ميخواهم ونه تاج و تخت رو
I don't want anything.
من هي ي نمي خوام.
Have you ever loved someone?
تا حالا عاشق شدي؟
Iove? -No? You should.
عشق؟ -- نه که نشدي ؟ بايد اونو تجربه کني ، عشق رو.
Brother, he is trying to trick us again.
برادر ، اون داره سعي ميکنه دوباره ما رو فريب بده.
So, you've returned? You remembered Magadha?
تو برشتي؟ ماادها بياد تو بود
Forgive me, Your Majesty. I wanted to...
مرا ببخش، اعليحضرت. من مي خواستم به...
A rebellion is threatened in Ujjaini. Go there.
يو جاينين دست به شورش زده ، به آنجا بريد
Any problem?
مشکلي داريد؟
No, Your Majesty.
نه ، اعليحضرت.
Are you missing Pawan? -Yes.
داري به اون فکر ميکني؟ -- بله.
He said that should I think of him I should call his name out loud.
يادت هست؟ اون فت باصداي بلند صداش بزنيم اون ميشنوه
Then, he'll appear.
سس ، او ظاهر مي شود.
Should I call him?
انجامش بديم؟
You call out as well.
توهم صدا بزن
Prince...
شاهزاده...
I must go. -His highness has ordered...
من بايد برم. -- حضرت والا دستور داده است تا...
Don't worry. You go to Ujjaini. I will meet you there.
نران نباشيد ،به يوجاينين بريد ، منهم خودم رو به شما ميرسونم
Despite the talk, I was sure you were all safe.
با وجود تمام شايعات ،من مطمعن بودم كه شما سالميد
Who would want to kill Prince Arya?
ه كسي قصد كشتن شاهزاده آريا رو داره؟
At first I suspected you.
قبل ازهمه من به شما مشكوكم
And I suspected you.
و منهم به شما مشکوکم .
At times like this friends suspect one another.
توي يه همين مواقعي كه دو دوست به همديه مزنون ميشن.
Bring Prince Arya here at the earliest. I cannot contain the senate any longer.
كسي برنده است كه بتونه نظراعضاء مجلس سنا  رو نسبت به اينكه كي شاهزاده آريا رو به قتل رسونده جلب كرد
You are right.
شما درست مي يد.
Don't go alone, General.
آيا به تنهايي ، ميتوني با همه مبارزه كني؟.
I need no one. -You do.
من نياز به هي کس ندارم. -- صبر كن ‍دوست من.
The enemy is very cunning.
دشمن بسيار حيله راست.
Where are Prince Arya and Princess Kaurwaki?
کجا هستند شاهزاده آريا ورنسس كرواكي؟
Burn this village, burn everything...
دهكده رو بسوزونيد ؟همه يز رو بسوزونيد
either they'll come out or burn alive.
اه بيرون نياييد زنده زنده سوزانده ميشيد
Where are Prince Arya and Princess Kaurwaki?
کجا هستند شاهزاده آريا ورنسس كرواكي؟
No. Stop.
صبر كنيد
Stop, we are here.
صبركنيد ، ما اينجاييم
Please let them be, I beg you.
به آنها كاري نداشته باش، التماست ميكنم. ولم كن
Kaurwaki.
كرواكي
Good that I found you. That woman, she said...
ه خوب شد كه ديدمتون ،داشتم از اون زن ميرسيدم
Where are Kaurwaki and Arya?
كرواكي و آريا كجايند؟
Bheema?
بهيم؟
Where is Kaurwaki?
كرواكي كجاست؟
What happened, Bheema?
ه اتفاقي افتاده ،بهيم؟
Bheema, where is Kaurwaki?
بهيم،كرواكي كجاست؟
Bheema...l ask you, Where is Kaurwaki?
بهيم، بهيم كرواكي كجاست؟
Here's your 20th tactic.
به اين مين تاكتيك 20
What about the 1 9th one?
ي ميي؟ اين بهتره يا تاكتيك 19؟
Speak up, friend. Your turn now. No running off today? You've lost?
يه زبونت بند اومده،نميتوني منو بزني؟ ، .
Get up.
بلند شو.
You're not even worth a thrashing.
تو حتي بدرد خرمن كوبي هم نميخوري
What's this? lost your mind?
اين يه،يكار ميكني؟ ديونه شدي؟
Iet go of my hand. Iet go.
،هي، دستم رو ول كن
Who are you people?
شما ديه كي هستيد؟
Iet me go.
ولم كنيد.
Wait.
صبر کنيد.
But Prince Asoka, he tried to... -Spare him.
اما شاهزاده آشوك اون داشت... -- تمومش كنيد
'Prince' Asoka?
شاهزاده، آشوك؟
You'll stay here. -Pawan is waiting for me.
شما همين اينجا بمانيد. -- اون منتظر ماست.
His kind never return.
اون ديه نمياد
He will, Bheema. His horse is here.
اون مياد بهيم، اون بااسبش رفته و زود مياد.
How is the wound now, friend... Prince?
كجات زخمي شده ،دوست م... شاهزاده؟
Prince, my problem is that my fist moves faster than my mind.
كار كنم،مشكل من اينه كه مشتم جلوتر از عقلم تصميم مييره
Why haven't you left?
تو كار اشتباهي نكردي؟
How could l?
ي داري ميي،
You saved my life. It's my duty to guard you for life.
تو زندي منو نجات دادي اين وظيفه منه كه به شما خدمت كنم .
From now, in war and victory, Virat will stand by you.
از  اين به بعد، درتمام جنها تا يروزي كامل ،من كنار شماهستم.
I want death not victory.
من مر ميخوام ، نه يروزي
Was she beautiful, Prince?
خيلي زيبا بود، رنس؟
Very.
خيلي.
Are you going to Pawan? -Yes.
كرواكي ،داري ميري دنبال اون؟ -- بله.
I will come too.
منم ميام.
You will not. You will go to Kalinga with Bheema.
تو جايي نمياي،توهمراه بهيم به كالين ميري
If I don't go, you don't either. Should I call Bheema?
اه منو نبري ، توهم نميتوني بري ،داد ميزنم
Call him.
داد بزن.
Come on.
بريم.
Iets take Pawan's horse with us too.
ما خيلي با اون فاصله داريم ،اسب نميخوايم؟
How much longer? -I don't know.
قدر فاصله داريم؟ --  نمي دونم.
Asoka's winning war after war. He seems undaunted by death.
آشوك بعداز يروزي در جن ،خيلي بي روا شده،بنظر ميرسه هي ترسي از مردن نداره
Each victory is a step closer to the throne.
او باهر يروزي يك قدم به تاج و تخت نزديكتر ميشه
You must stop him at Ujjaini itself.
وتو بايد اين قدمها رو توي يوجانين متوقف كني سوشيم.
Friend.
دوست من
Do you know any Pawan? A soldier in the Magadha Army, rides a horse.
سربازي به اسم اون ميشناسيد؟اون توي ارتش ماادها است
No.
نه نميشناسم
Iet's go. It's raining.
كرواكي بيا بريم،داره بارون مياد
Come.
بيا
No herb or medicine is helping him.
هي دارويي بهش كمك نميكنه
How does one save the life of a man who has no desire to live?
طور ميشه كسي رو كه ميلي به زنده موندن نداره رو با دارو نجات داد
Kaur...waki, Kaur...waki.
كر...واكي, كر...واكي.
'Kaurwaki'?
كرواكي؟
Prime Minister, where is Asoka? -I don't know.
آشوك كجاست ، نخست وزير -- من نمي دانم.
You don't? Or are you hiding something?
نميدوني ؟ يا داري از من مخفي ميكني؟
Why all this loyalty to Asoka?
را اينهمه به آشوك وفاداري؟
My loyalty is to the throne of Magadha.
من به هركسي كه بر تخت ماادها بنشيند وفا دارم
Prince Asoka is getting better, isn't he?
شاهزاده آشوك بهتر شده ، نه؟
Physical wounds will heal. But wounds of the heart...
زخم روي بدن خوب ميشه. اما زخم قلب...
Haven't you seen how he calls out her name even in his sleep?
ناش كنيد، حتي توي خواب هم اونو احساس ميكنه واسمش رو مياره
Kaurwaki, Kaurwaki, Kaurwaki.
كرواكي،كرواكي،كرواكي
Are you crying?
داري ريه ميكني؟
You see, my heart is rather tender.
ببينيد، قلب من بد جوري رفته.
Kaurwaki was very lovely? -Yes.
كرواكي خيلي دوست داشتني بود ؟ -- بله.
But you are too. You too. And you, most of all.
اما توهم خيلي خوشلي. توهم خوشلي. و تو ، بيشتر از همه خوشلي.
What kind of love is this that lives on even after death?
اين ه عشقيه ، كه حتي بعداز مر هم زندي ميكنه؟
When you left you did not look back even once.
وقتي برشتي وبهم ناه كردي ،حس كردم كه ديه نميبينمت
A bright glow
يک نور درخشان
pervades
سايه افکنده
and fills
و ر
your eyes
شم خود را
Your eyes warn...
به همه هشدار ميده ...
''Don't touch me''
''به من دست نزنيد''
Your dreams too...
روياهاي خود را بيش از حد...
are reflected
منعکس مي شوند
in your eyes
در شم شما
I've searched and searched for you...
در من جستجو و جستجو را براي شما...
In the sweep of the skies above
در رفت و برشت از آسمان بالا
hoping to find you encased in a cloud
اميد به شما در روکشي از ابر
I have looked and looked for you
من ناه کرد و ناه براي شما
in every nook and corner
در هر وشه و وشه
hoping to spy you walking on a river bank
اميد به جاسوسي شما راه رفتن در بانک رودخانه
I held on to time
برزار شد در تاريخ به زمان
To ask where you are
براي برسيد که در آن شما
I asked the river
رسيدم رودخانه
and the vast ocean
و از اقيانوس هناور
I walked the crest of waves
من راه مي رفت تاج امواج
feeling your caress
احساس نوازش شما
Stop. What are you doing?
توقف. ه کار مي کنيد؟
I won't let you kill this harmless bird.
من اجازه نمي دم اين رنده بي آزار رو بکشيد
Move away.
برو كنار
Why? It deserves to live as much as I do.
را؟ اه ميتوني بزن،زندي اون ،زندي منه.
Move ! -Release the arrow.
برو كنار! -- ميتوني بزن،بزن.
Devi...
ديوي....
Where were you, Devi? The ceremony awaits you.
كجا بودي ديوي ؟همه توي مراسم منتظر تو اند
Come, dear, come here.
بيا، بيا دخترم.
She's eXquisite.
دختر خوبيست
They make a lovely couple.
اين دوبهم ميايند و زوج خوشبختي ميشوند
I met Prince Asoka today...
اموز شاهزاده آشوك رو ديدم
She's so shy. She's quite spirited though.
اويكم خجالتي است. ولي راز روحيه.
He's become so vicious.
اون خيلي مرموزه
Everyone's scared of him but not me.
همه ازش ميترسند ،ولي من اصلا
Why whisper? Tell us too. What do you think of our son?
ي داريد زمزمه ميكنيد؟ . نظرت درمورد سر ما يه؟
Tell me, dear. Are you happy?
بهم بو عزيزم. اونو ميسندي؟
Congratulations, she has agreed.
تبريک مي م ، اون موافقت کرده .
Asoka's in Ujjaini, badly wounded. -Take advantage of this, Sugatra.
آشوك توي يوجاينين، بشدت زخمي شده.. -- تو بايد از اين فرست استفاده كني ،سوكاترا
How? He is guarded on all sides. It's impossible to break through.
ه طوري؟ دور تا دور اونو محافظ رفته،غير ممكنه بشه نزديكش شد. .
Difficult but not impossible.
سخت هست ،ولي غير ممكن نيست
Here, take this medicine.
دوست من، داروتون رو بخوريد
With this your fever will lessen and you'll sleep well.
اين دارو تب شما رو ايين مياره وراحت ميتونيد بخوابيد
It's Devi's wedding today. She won't be here.
امروز عروسيه ديوي است . اون نيستش.
Today, you will listen to me instead. Drink it?
وامروز ،بايد از من اطاعت كني .بنوشيد
A little more?
کمي بيشتر؟
I forgot to apply the herbal paste on Prince Asoka's wounds.
داروي شاهزاده آشوك رو ندادم
Grandmother, I'll be back soon.
مادر بزر ، من الان برميردم.
Make something for me as well.
يزي براي منهم هست.
Halt.
صبركن.
What are you taking inside? -Medicine.
ي داري ميبري؟ -- جوشانده.
Go in.
برو، برو.
Pass me some water, please.
كمي آب بده، لطفا.
Who's there? Wait. What are you feeding him?
كي هستي؟ صبر کن. ي بهش ميدي؟
Iet go.
نميزارم.
Friend?
دوست من؟
Prince Asoka? Here?
شاهزاده آشوك؟ اينجا؟
How did this happen?
ي شده ، بهت ميم؟
Come on let's go.
بيا بريم،اشو
This wedding cannot be.
اين عروسي انجام نميشه.
Where are you going? Please don't go.
كجا ميريد؟ صبر كنيد
It's no fault of this child.
اين به هي تقصيري نداره.
You've no right to ruin her life like this.
شما حق نداريد، زندي اين دو تا رو خراب كنيد.
I will not let you leave.
بررديد ،من اجازه نميدم بريد
I request you to please wait.
من از شما خواهش ميكنم ،بمانيد
If the Prince's request is a command, we will not leave.
اه شاهزاده اجازه بدهند ما بريم ،برمن منت نهادند
Poor Devi. Who will marry her now?
حالا تكليف ديوي ي ميشه
You won't push me again, will you?
تو كه خيال نداري دوباره منو هل بدي؟
My warrior.
رنسس من.
Did she love you as much as you love her?
اونو خيلي دوست داشتي؟
I know that only Kaurwaki lives in your heart.
من ميدونم ، كه تنها كرواكي درون قلب شماست
I cannot take her place.
من نميتونم جاي اونو بيرم
Please forgive me, Devi.
لطفا مرا ببخش،ديوي
Why? There's so much love in your heart. Maybe my destiny...
را؟همين مقدار عشق هم براي من كافيه،بهر حال اين سرنوشت منه
No. It's not love, only pain.
عشق نه ،درد
Iove wounds in a way that does not let you live or die.
در راه عشق،فقط درد ورنج نصيبت ميشه ،تا هنام مر
If I had seen her just one last time.
اي كاش براي يك لحظه،ميتونستم اونو ببينم
Kaurwaki is right here with you, in your heart.
كرواكي اينجاست،در قلب تو،در نفس تو
But where was I when she needed me?
اما کجا بودم من، موقعي که اون بهم نياز داشت؟
I promised her...
من به او قول  داده بودم...
that while I was there she would come to no harm.
تا زماني كه هستم نزارم هي آسيبي بهش برسه
Where was l, Devi?
من كجا بودم ديوي؟
Where was I when she was dying?
کجا بودم من هنامي که او در حال مر بود؟
Where, when she took Pawan's name in her parting breath?
كار كنم ؟طور ميتونم دوري كرواكي رو تحمل كنم؟
The intoXication of our night together
منتظرم شب بشه
Has not left me
تو يشم برردي
The sensuousness of your body is still entwined in my arms
احساسات از بدن تو وقتي كه  در آغوش مني
I opened my eyes but that didn't disturb my dream
اما شمام رو كه باز كردم ديدم فقط يه روياست
Yes. I recall
بله. به خاطر دارم...
Yes. I do
بله. به خاطر دارم
The dream which your lips gifted me stays with each breath I take
رويايي که لب خود را با استعداد من با هر نفس من  باقي مي ماند
Even in your absence
حتي در غياب شما
The thought of you eXcites me
فکر  شما مرا برانيخته
When I turn over in my sleep my dream just takes another hue
وقتي که من به نوبه خود در خواب هستم ميخواهم اين رويا طول بكشد
When the thought of you enters my mind
زماني که فکر شما وارد ذهن من
those moments bubble under a sheet of water
اين حباب لحظه در زير يک ورقه از آب
My body is on fire
بدن من در آتش
Yes. I recall
بله. به خاطر دارم
The seasons that bind you to me are countless
وقتي كه مرا لمس ميكني نسيمي از كلمات بيشمار حسميكنم
They contain promise of several lifetimes
آنها حاوي وعده هايي زيادي  ازطول عمر است
My sorrows are trivial
غم مرا رها ميكند
I wish for a long night and a longer day
من آرزوي يك شب طولاني ويك روز طولاني تر دارم
I wish for a life endless enough to contain our togetherness
وآرزوي يك زندي ابدي براي باهم بودن
Yes, I recall Yes, I do
بله ، به ياد مي آورم بله ، من
The dream your lips have gifted me lingers with each breath I take.
روياي لمس كردن لبهاي تو رو براي بهتر نفس كشيدن دارم
I am looking for Pawan, a soldier in the Magadha Army.
من بدنبال شخصي به اسم اون ميردم اون توي ارتش ماادها ست
Pawan? We don't know.
اون ؟ كدوم اون؟
Ask her, she knows everything.
از اونها برسيد ، آنها همه يز رو ميدانند
I too waited for a long time for him but he never came back.
منم خيلي وقته كه منتظرشم ولي اون، هي وقت نيامد
What kind of people are these?
اينها ديه ه مردمانيند؟
Come on, let's go.
بيا، بيا بريم.
As per your wish, your highness. We have served food to all.
همانطور كه شما فرموديد ،به همه يه اندازه غذا رسيده
Eat well, such a feast is rare.
خوب غذا بخوريد، از اين روزها خيلي كمه.
Mother, look. she is Devi, the girl that Prince Asoka has married.
ببين مادر ، اون دختره زن شاهزاده آشوكه ،اسمش ديوي است
Please serve to those there and those too.
لطفا به اونهاي كه اونجا نشسته اند هم برسيد
Have you heard? Prince Asoka is returning to Magadha with Devi.
هي منلهاي من، خبر تازه رو شنيديد شاهزاده آشوك، با دختري به اسم ديوي به ماادها اومده
The stars predict tension in their marriage.
آره ،منم توي ستاره ها ازدواجشون رو ديدم
You and your stars. They're married so what tension could there be?
تو ميخواي با ستارهاي  در حال ازدواجت ما رو بكشي؟
Here, eat sweetmeats.
بفرماييد ، شيريني
Why are you distributing sweets? -His wife gave birth to a son.
را شيريني خش ميكنيد؟ -- خانمش يه سر زاييده.
But you have not been home for more than a year, right?
اما تو كه مدت كميه كه ازدواج كردي؟
We were his emissaries in love. -But...
آخه اونا خيلي عاشق هم هستند. -- اما...
No buts... give your sweets and go.
آخه ماخه نكن شيرينيت رو بخور و برو
Iong live Prince Asoka.
شاهزاده آشوك ، زنده باد
You're here to see Prince Asoka as well?
توهم اومدي شاهزاده آشوك رو ببيني؟
No, I am looking for Pawan.
نه، من بدنبال اون ميردم
Iook who's coming.
از اينجا بريم تا ما رو نديده
Iet's go from here. Come Arya.
زود باشيد بريم،بيا آريا
I will not go. -Enough of this madness.
من نميخوام بيام -- بس كن ،اين همه ديوانه بازي رو
You have looked for him enough. -I will not leave without Pawan.
يكمي بيشتر فكر كن ،بيا بريم -- من اون رو ترك نميكنم
Do as you please. Iook for your Pawan.
باشه  با ما نيا،ولي توي اينها تو اون ميبيني؟
When you're done, return to Kalinga. Prince Arya. Iet's go.
ما به كلين بر ميرديم ،توهم كارت تموم شد ميتوني بياي بريم شاهزاده آريا
I don't want to go.
من نميخوام بيام.
Bheema, let go.
من نميخوام بيام ،بهيم ،ولم كن
He acted as he thought appropriate. Give him my blessings.
اون كار درستي نكرده اون دشمن منه.
Your Majesty, at least meet him once.
حضرت والا ، حداقل اونو ملاقات كنيد فقط يک بار.
There is no place for a Buddhist girl in this family.
توي اين خانواده جايي براي دختر بودايي نيست
Tell Asoka to return to Ujjaini.
آشوك بايد به يوجاينين بررده
General. We feared that even you...
ژنرال ، همه ما ترسيده بوديم نكنه شما هم مرده باشيد
General, I promise you...
ژنرال ، من به شما قول مي دهم...
Whoever conspired to kill Prince Arya...
تمام كساني كه توي توطعه مر شاهزاده  بودند ...
will be severely punished.
بشدت مجازات ميشوند.
No need of that. Prince Arya and Princess Kaurwaki are alive.
نيازي به اين كار نيست ،شاهزاده آريا زنده هستند،وهمينطور رنسس كرواكي
Impossible.
غير ممکن است.
Arya...
آريا...
This is not possible.
اين امکان ذير نيست.
You have lost, Prime Minister. Your conspiracy misfired.
شما باختيد، نخست وزير ، همه اين توطعه ها زير سر تو بوده
A lie. I have served Kalinga all my life.
اينها همش دروغه ، من تمام عمرم به كولين خدمت كردم
I am innocent.
من بي ناهم.
Forgive me, Minister. They've come to know.
مرا ببخش، وزير. اونا منو شناسايي كردند
Take him away.
بمن ناه كن،بمن ناه كن
Such a traitor should be sentenced to death.
اين خايُن بايد اعدام بشه
Take him away. -I am innocent.
از جلوي شمام دورش كنيد -- من بي ناهم.
Didn't I promise you that we will be together in Kalinga?
يادته بهت قول دادم كه به كالين برتون ميردونم ؟
Yes, only Pawan is not with us.
آره ، ولي حيف كه اون با ما نيست
How much longer will you wait for him?
تا كي ، تاكي ميخواي صبر كني؟
Till his return.
تا موقعي كه بررده.
If he doesn't?
اه بر نشت؟
That could be. But I'll still wait for him.
اون مياد، من منتظرش ميمونم.
You knew I would not spare your life.
تو ميدوني كه من زندي برام بي اهميته.
Even then, you joined hands with Susima?
را با سوشيم دست به يكي كردي ؟ ها؟
What's your life worth now? Answer me?
را بخاطر زنده موندت جوابم رو نميدي؟ را جواب نميدي؟
What is it?
يه؟
I must tell you something.
من بايد مطلبي رو بهت بم
Go on.
حالا بو
Calm down first.
اه آروم نشي يزي نميم
What is it?
يه ؟
A son? My son?
يک سر؟ سر من؟
I will teach him everything.
من بهش همه ي ياد ميدم
Everything.
همه ي.
I will teach him to fight with the sword.
من بهش ياد ميدم طور از شمشير استفاده كنه
I will teach him to fight like a warrior.
من اونو يه جنجو بارميارم
My son.
سر من.
The first heir to the Mauryan empire.
Mauryan وارث اولين امراتوري .
The Emperor of Magadha.
Magadhaامراتور.
I will take him in my arms and put him on the throne.
من اونو در آغوش مييرم وبه تخت مينشانم.
What if it is a daughter?
اه دختر بشه ي؟
No. It will be a son.
هرز ، هرز دختر نميشه.
Go and tell Susima, it will be a son, the emperor of Magadha.
برو وبه سوشيم بو ، اون دختر نميشه ، Magadhaامراتور .
Wasn't it your dream that I sit on the throne?
آرزوي شما اين بود که من برتخت بشينم؟
I give you my word I will strive to be an able King.
من به شما قول ميدم که همه سعي خودم رو ميکنم تا ادشاهي مقتدر بشم.
You will be proud of your Susima.
شما حتما به سوشيم افتخار خواهيد کرد.
Devi is eXpecting.
ديوي بارداره
Susima, the word is out that an heir is to be born.
به ياد داشته باش،Susima که به آشوک همين روزها بدنيامياد .
Asoka's son will occupy the throne. -The people will never accept him.
سر آشوک صاحب تاج و تخت ميشه ، مردم هم-- هرز.
Am I right, pundit-ji? -That's right.
وش کن، اون نميتونه به تخت بشينه درسته دانشمند؟ -کاملا درسته-
A son born of a Buddhist mother cannot claim the throne.
فرزند متولد شده از مادر بودايي نمي تواند ادعاي تاج و تخت بکند.
The people have no choice, Susima.
، Susimaاينو بدون که مردم اين يزا حاليشون نيست.
And you? You're incapable of producing an heir.
و شما؟در حال حاضر هي وارثي نداريد.
It's destiny.
آينده.
You tell me, Pundit-ji. What fate awaits Asoka's child?
شما  بوييد ، دانشمند، . ه آينده اي در انتظار سر آشوک هست
Think before you answer, pundit-ji.
قبل از جواب دادن خوب فکر کن ،ه آينده اي در انتظار فرزند آشوک هست؟
Asoka's son will not live.
سر آشوک نبايد به دنيا بياد .
Destiny. It's all destiny.
آينده . اين تمام آينده است.
Who is there?
کي اينجاست؟
There is someone here. Soldier.
اينجا ي ميخواي . سرباز
Everybody leave. -Friend?
همه برن بيرون. --
I said, everyone leave.
فتم، همه بيرون.
Ieave.
بريد .
Come.
بياييد.
Speak to me, Mother.
با من حرف بزن مادر ، مادر..
Please, Mother. Talk to me.
با من حرف بزن مادر.
I did all that you asked me to. Please, Mother, talk to me once.
هر کاري که بي انجام ميدم ،فقط با من حرف بزن.
Speak to me just once, for just one moment.
فقط يک بار بو ، يک لحظه بو.
If something happens to you, all hell will break loose.
اه بفهمم کي اين بلا رو سرت آورده زنديش رو جهنم ميکنم
I will destroy everything. Everything.
همه يز رو از بين ميبرم. همه يز.
Vitasoka, tell Mother to talk to me.
هي ويتاشوک ،به مادر بو با من حرف بزنه.
Please, speak to me.
لطفا ، با من صحبت کن.
Please don't. -Don't stop me today.
اين کار رو نکن. -- برو کنار.
Somebody has to stop.
تو نميدوني  کار کيه.
Anger destroys everything. -Then let it.
خشمت رو کنترول کن. -- تو فقط برو کنار.
I will never let you touch my child with a killer's hands.
برو ، ولي يادت باشه که نميزارم يه قاتل سرم رو لمس کنه
So, you've come to kill your brother?
هي آشوک، تو اومدي برادر خودت رو بکشي؟
Kill me.
من رو بكش.
Pick up the sword, Susima.
شمشيرت رو بردار ، سوشيم.
What about your mother's death? Take your revenge, Asoka.
توي مر مادرت منو مقصر ميدوني ؟ اومدي انتقام بيري آشوک.
Why hesitate? Go ahead, kill me.
را وايسادي ؟ بيا جلو، منو بکش.
Pick up the sword, Susima.
شمشيرت رو بردار ، سوشيم.
Your mother was like my own. I'd love your son as my own.
مادر تو ، مادر منم بود اون منوبا عشق توي آغوش خودش ميرفت.
Only if you were not Asoka. But you are Asoka. It's destiny.
فقط اينو بدون آشوک،. که اين سرنوشت ماست آشوک.
Pick up the sword, Susima.
شمشيرت رو بردار، سوشيم
To help you defeat me?
را؟ ميخواي بهت کمک کنم؟
I won't allow you that pleasure.
نه آشوک ، بهت اين لذت رو نميدم
Iet history note that Asoka did not win the throne...
ميخواي توي تاريخ بنويسند که آشوک وسوشيم بر سر تاج و تخت جنيدند
he had to kill to get it.
آشوک يروز شد وصاحب تاج وتخت شد؟.
Pick up the sword, Susima. -No.
شمشيرت رو بردار، سوشيم -- هرز
I was not a murderer, Asoka. You left me with no choice.
منو بکش آشوک، تو اره ديه اي نداري---
Moment to moment I lived in fear of your snatching the throne from me.
لحظه به لحظه من در ترس زندي مي کردم که يه وقت نياي و تاج و تخت رو ازم بدزدي
To sit on the throne you must kill your own brother.
براي نشستن بر تخت سلطنت تو بايد برادر خودت رو بکشي.
You will have to become 'Susima'.
تو بايد براي تبديل شدن به ادشاه  '.
Kill me, Asoka. Kill me. You need courage to sit on the throne...
. منو بکشي. منو بکش ،آشوک براي نشستن به تخت بايد شجاع باشي
and also to kill your brother.
و همين طور براي کشتن برادر خود ت.
Kill me, Asoka.
منو بکش ، آشوک
I knew that you are incapable of killing your siblings.
من ميدونستم که تو قادر به کشتن خواهر و برادرت نيستي
I know you cannot.
من مي دونم که تو نمي توني.
That's why the throne is mine, not your's.
به همين علت تاج و تخت مال منه
Destiny...
سرنوشت...
What should I do with the brothers?
با برادران ه بايد بکنيم قربان؟
Kill them all.
همه آنها رو بکشيد.
I have killed all my brothers, Susima.
من هم برادران رو ميکشم
Now can I sit on the throne?
حالا ديه ميتونم به تخت بشينم؟
Iong live King Asoka.
مها راج آشوک کين ، زنده باد.
What's the matter? Why are you all so quiet?
هي منل هاي من، را اينقدر ساکت شديد؟
There's nothing left to say.
يزي برا فتن نيست.
Asoka killed all his brothers. And no one said a word.
آشوک تمام برادرهاش رو کشت وکسي حرفي زد؟
Who can say anything? Even King Bindusara is no more.
کي ميتونه يزي به ؟ اون ديه ادشاهه
Entire Magadha is terror-struck.
کل ماادها مرده اند.
Strange.
عجيب و غريب.
Keep quiet, idiot.
نيزه رو درست بير  ، ادم سفيه و احمق .
Know what people are saying? An evil man now rules over Magadha.
به مردم ي بيم؟ يه مرد بد در راس ماادها قرار رفته ،وليعهد آشوک
'Evil' Asoka.
شيطان آشوک
You will not go anywhere, Devi. You know I will not let you go.
ديوي، از اين به بعد هي جا بدون اجازه من نميري .
I am leaving. -What was I to do?
من مي روم. -- تو ي فتي؟
They killed Mother. I should forgive them?
آنها مادر منو کشتن وتو ميي بايد ببخشمشون؟
Yes.
بله
I don't have such a big heart.
من همين قلب بزري ندارم.
I know. That's why I am leaving.
ميدونم. به همين دليله که ميخوام برم.
You are not leaving.
تو جايي نميري
I am going.
هرز- من ميرم.
You should know. Where is Sugatra hiding?
تو بايد بدوني که سوکاترا کجاست اون کجاست؟
He won't say anything. He does not know.
اون هري ميدونست فت اون خبر نداره
Then his life is meaningless.
س زنده موندنت بي معنيه.
Friend, please stop. Enough.
دوست من ، بس کن ديه کافيه.
Nothing will stop me now, Virat.
هي يز در حال حاضر نميتونه منو متوقف کنه
I will be the greatest emperor on earth.
من بزرترين امرا تور بر روي زمين ميشم.
Greater than King Bindusara, stronger than Chandragupta Maurya.
Bindusaraبزرتر از ادشاه Chandragupta Mauryaقوي تر از
The greatest, ever.
بزرترين، .
Susima said, ''To rule an empire, to be a great Emperor...
همون طور که سوشيم فت ،بزرترين امراتور شدن،  ،
one needs to kill.''
بدون کشتن نميشه
Please rest, Prince Sugatra. Give the senate time to think about it.
شاهزاده سوکوترا ، لطفا اجازه بديد سنا در اين مورد بيشتر فکر کنه
My death is certain if Kalinga does not grant me asylum.
اه کاليناه منو نذيره ، مر من حتميه
I plead with the senate of Kalinga to protect my life.
از مجلس سناي کليناه تقاضا دارم براي حفظ جانم با ناهندي من موافقت کنند
Kalinga has given asylum to Sugatra.
سوکوترا رفته به کاليناه و ناهنده شده
Why? Had they not heard my order?
را؟ مه تقاضاي من رو بهشون نفتي؟
They say Kalinga owes nothing to a man who killed his brothers.
آنها فتند کاليناه به کسي که همه برادرانش رو ميکشه کمکي نميکنيم
My relationship with Kalinga is a strange one.
کالين ، کالين ، يه رابطه عجيب بين من و کالين هست
Till today no one has attacked Kalinga.
هيکس تا به امروز به کالينا حمله نکرده
Kalinga is a democracy.
کالينا تابع دموکراسيه.
Your grandfather dreamt of a united lndia.
در بزر شما خواب ديد که هند رو متحد ميکنه
Make that dream come true.
اين خواب به حقيقت نرسيد
Attack Kalinga.
حمله به کالينا
Kalinga.
کالينا.
We will always win.
ما هميشه يروزيم.
Pawan's with the Magadha Army. Will he too fight us?
اون هم با ارتش ماادها با ما مبارزه ميکنه؟
Pawan will never fight us. -That's true.
اون هيوقت اينکار رو نميکنه. -- درسته.
Order me, Your Majesty. I'll make them stare into the eyes of death.
من يشنهاد ميکنم که شماشون رو از کاسه در بياريم تا بقيه بترسند
Fear will render them useless. They will forget patriotism.
بعد از فرار  ، مشخص ميشه وطن رست واقعي کيه
What are you saying? Friend, this is against the rules of war.
ي ميي تو؟ دوست من ، اين بر خلاف مقررات جنه
War has only one rule, Virat. Victory.
توي جن فقط يک قايده وجود داره ويرات ، يروزي
We'll burn their houses, destroy their fields.
همه خانه و زمينهاي رأيت رو نابود کنيد
I told your father. This village, these homes, these people...
من به در خودم فتم . اين روستا ، اين خانه ها ، اين افراد...
all belong to Emperor Asoka. Which means all belong to me.
همه به امراتور آشوک تعلق داره ؟يعني به ما--
You too are mine.
تو هم مال مني
Your father is very brave.
در تو خيلي  شجاعي
Such cruelty? ls he human or a monster? Who is this Asoka?
قدر بيرحمند،اين آشوک هيولاست يا آدم؟
Why kill so many innocent people? -He'll do anything to win the war.
طور تونسته اين همه آدم بيناه رو بکشه؟ -- او براي يروزي در اين جن دست به هر کاري ميزنه.
He has not spared his own brothers. -Then he must die.
حتي برادرانش هم از دستش در امان نيستند. --  اون بايد بميره.
I can take you to Asoka. -Iet's go.
تو، منو براي رسيدن به آشوک راهنمايي کن -- بريم
Kalinga has attacked!
کالينا حمله کرده!
Iook, there he is.
ببينيد، اون اينجاست.
Sugatra?
سوکاترا؟
Come, come, Sugatra.
بيا،بيا، سوکاترا
You've missed your brothers so much that you came to meet them?
اومدي برادران از دست رفتت رو ملاقات کني؟
You want to fight me? One more time?
ميخواي با من مبارزه کني؟ دوباره؟
You won't face me?
من رو در رو با تو نميجنم
All right then, strike from behind.
من برميردم ، وتو از شت حمله کن.
Come Sugatra. Attack me !
بيا سوکاتره ، به من حمله کن
Come, attack me.
، حمله کن.
You can kill me... but you can never defeat Kalinga.
تو ميتوني منو بکشي ولي کالين رو هرز نميتوني شکست بدي
The Magadha flag will tower over blood-stained Kalinga.
من رم ماادها رو باخون  بر برج کالين مي افرازم
Give my greetings to Susima, my loving brother.
سلام منو به برادر عزيزم سوشم برسون
What will become of us, now. How will we fight this war?
حالا کار کنيم، طور با اونها مبارزه کنيم؟
This is not mere soil. It is our ancestral heritage.
اين خاک بي مصرف نيست. اين ميراث اجدادي ما است.
Nobody can take it from us.
هي کس نمي تونه اونو از ما بيره.
Should we lose, what will we tell our children?
ما نبايد اونو از دست بديم ، فردا به به هامون ي بيم؟
Why should we lose? Why should we not fight?
بيم ي شد که از دستش داديم؟ را براش مبارزه نکرديم؟؟
We will fight... together !
ما مبارزه ميکنيم، همه باهم!
All my sons were killed in the war. Had I one more, he would fight too.
همه سران من در جن کشته شدند. اه يکي ديه هم داشتم ، براي مبارزه با آنها ميدادم.
She is my daughter. Now she will fight.
اين دختر منه. حالا ديه اون هم مبارزه ميکنه.
Every man in Kalinga will fight. -Every woman in Kalinga will fight.
همه بخاطر کالين ميجنيم -- زن ومرد براي کالين ميجنيم
Yes, we will all fight !
بله ، ما همي خواهيم جنيد!
You don't know him. He will do anything to defeat Kalinga.
شما اونو نميشناسيد ، اون براي شکست دادن کالين هر کاري ميکنه
At any cost he wants victory.
اون به هر قيمتي ميخواد يروز بشه.
Only victory.
فقط يروزي.
My wish is that when my child opens his eyes...
آرزوي من اين است که ، وقتي  فرزندم  شماشو باز کرد...
he should see only love not death.
فقط عشق باشه نه مر ومير
The first words he hears should be of love, not shrieks of pain.
اولين کلماتي که مشنوه درد نباشه ، بلکه عشق باشه
Everything will be destroyed. Everything.
همه يز نابود خواهد شد. همه يز.
Where to, friend? -A war awaits me. Have you forgotten?
کجا ،دوست عزيز؟ -- ميدان جن در انتظار منه ،  فراموش کردي؟
Before that you have to fight another war.
قبل از اون بايد با يکي مبارزه کني
Really? Who is this new enemy?
واقعا؟ اين دشمن جديد کيه؟
The one who stands in front of you.
کسي که در مقابل شما ايستاده .
No. You are a friend, my only friend.
نه ،تو دوست مني ، دوست عزيز من
Then listen to your friend and stop. Enough !
س به حرفام وش کن وتمومش کن
When will you stop killing innocent people?
تا کي ميخواي به کشتن مردم بي ناه ادامه بدي
How much longer will you fight?
تا کي ميخواي بجني؟
Till I win.
تايروزي
Till I win it all.
تا برهمه يروز شوم.
Then today you will not win over me.
س بايد اول در مبارزه با من يروز بشي
One moment...
صبر کنيد...
You will kill your own friend? -I will go to any length to stop you.
تو ميخواي دوست خودت رو بکشي؟ -- من به هر قيمتي که شده ميخوام متوقفت کنم.
Remember, friend, the 1 9th tactic?
يادت مياد ، دوست من، تاکتيک 19؟
Enough, Virat ! -No ! Never.
کافي ديه ، ويرات -- نه! هرز.
You're alive... because you are a friend
دليل زنده بودنت اينه که دوست مني
You are nobody's friend.
من دوست تو نيستم
You are your own enemy.
تو با خودت هم دشمني
That's why you are called 'Evil' Asoka !
ونکه تو رو به نام آشوک شيطان ميشناسند
Today we'll have a feast in Kalinga.
امروز بايد توي کالين جشن بيريم
But Emperor Asoka has not come yet.
اما امراطور آشوک هنوز نرسيده
You don't need elephants to crush ants.
لازم نيست فيل براي له کردن موره بياد
Charge !
حمله
Come on, move back !
عقب نشيني کنيد ، عقب نشيني!
Follow them.
حمله کنيد
Cowards ! Running away from the battle field?
ترسوها ،فرارميکنيد،
Pawan !
اون
We have lost the war. -We cannot lose.
ما باختيم. -- ما نبايد ببازيم.
I will go and fight. We cannot lose !
من ميرم و ميجنم. ما نبايد ببازيم!
Please don't go, Prince. Please stop.
رنس ، لطفا نريد. خواهش ميکنم نريد کارواکي، کارواکي.
What happened, Vitasoka?
ه شده ، ويتاشوک
You wanted to be a poet. Then why this guise?
ميخواستي يه شاعر بشي، اين لباسها يه؟
I know what you want to say. The tormentor Asoka ! Evil Asoka !
من ميدونم ي ميخواي بي ، همه رو قبلا شنيدم، آشوک شيطان
Is that what you want to tell me? I have heard it all before.
اومدي اينها رو بي درسته؟ من همه رو قبلا شنيدم.
I have come to tell you that you have become a father.
خير براي فتن اينها نيامدم اومدم بم که تو در شدي
My son !
سر من
Mahendra is your son and Sanghamitra is your daughter.
Mahendra سرت Sanghamitra و دخترت.
Where is Devi, Vitasoka?
ديوي کجاست ، ويتا شوک
I am their father, Vitasoka.
من درشان هستم ،ويتاشوک
You are only an Emperor. Emperor Asoka.
تو فقط امرا توري ،امراتور
Donning another garb does not change the truth, Vitasoka.
وشيدن لباس ديران تغيري در حقيقت نيست، ويتاشوک
War is the truth. Wars happen. In war, you either win or die.
جن يه حقيقته. جن اتفاق مي افته. وتو هم در جن ، يا برنده اي يا بازنده.
And I have won, Vitasoka! I have won.
ومن برنده شدم  ويتاشوک ،برنده
Yes, you have. You have won the tears of widows...
بله ، شما برنده شديد ونتيجه اون اشک زنان بيوه است
the cries of orphans and enflamed bodies.
ريه يتيم وبدن اره شده آنها
You have won it all.
تمام يزهايي که شما برديد اينها هستند
Vitasoka, I have won.
من بردم ، ويتاشوک
We've never collected so much wealth in any other war, as this.
ما ثروت زيادي بدست آورديم ، اه جن بعدي اينطور باشه قدر خوبه
We've never killed so many people
ديه جني در کار نيست ، ما آدمهاي زيادي رو کشتيم
The bigger the victory, the more the wealth !
يروزي يعني ثروت
You have stumbled on a fortune, such a beautiful and strong horse.
اه با ثروتمون يه اسب به اين زيبايي هم يرمون ميومد قدر خوب ميشد
They say it belongs to 'Kaurwaki', the one who inspired...
کرواکي رو ديدي ، مين اون  اربابشون بوده
the farmers and women to fight against Magadha's army.
کشاورزا رو عليه ارتش ماادها دور هم جمع کرده
Who cares? The horse will fetch a handsome price.
ه احميتي داره؟ بنظرت اسب خوشتيي مثل اين قدر مي ارزه.
Kaurwaki...
کرواکي...
Water...
آب ...
You have not won...
تو يروز نشدي
I'll never let you win.
من بهت اجازه نميدم يروز بشي
Kaurwaki.
کرواکي
I am alive ! You have to fight me.
من زنده ام!تو بايد با من مبارزه کني.
Throw down your sword Kaurwaki, the war is over.
شمشير رو بزار کنار کرواکي،جن تمام شده
The war is not over. You have to kill me too.
جن تمام نشده . تو بايد من رو هم بکشي.
How can I kill you? I am your Pawan.
طور ميتونم تو رو بکشم ،من اون تو هستم
You are not my Pawan. You are Asoka... Asoka !
تو اون من نيستي ،تو اون نيستي ، تو آشوکي، آشوک ، آشوک
Forgive me.
مرا ببخش.
Why did you not come?
تو براي ي اومدي ؟
I waited so long...
من تا آخرين لحظه منتظرت بودم...
Where did I not look for you? I searched everywhere.
را اين کاررو کردي، را اين کاررو کردي
Pawan...
اون
Arya !
آريا
Where were you?
تو کجا رفتي؟
Asoka took away all my land.
آشوک ميخواد سرزمين منو بيره
No one can take your land from you. It is your's.
هي کس نمي تونه اين سرزمين رو ازت بيره ، اون مال شماست، فقط شما
I have come back.
من اومدم.
You will not go again?
تو ديه نميخواي بري و مارو ترک کني؟
No, never again
نه ، هرز نه
Promise me?
قول ميدي؟
I promise.
قول مي دم.
See? I did not even cry.
مي بينيد؟ من حتي ريه هم نکردم.
Pawan? Did the prince return?
اون ، شاهزاده بر ميرده؟
Yes... he did.
بله...شاهزاده برميرده.
With horses and elephants?
با اسب ها و فيل ها؟
With hundreds of horses and elephants.
با صدها اسب و فيل.
Then?
بعدش؟
He took the princess on his horse and rode away.
اونو شاهزاده خانم سوار بر اسب به سرزمينهاي دور رفتند
Then?
و بعد؟
They lived together.
با هم  به زندي ادامه دادند.
Happily?
به خوبي و خوشي؟
Yes, very happily.
بله ، به خوبي و خوشي.
Pawan, it's getting dark.
اون ، همه جا رو تاريک ميبينم
The sun, moon and stars are fading.
آفتاب داره تاريک ميشه
No, Arya...
نه ، آريا
nothing will happen.
هيي نيست عزيزم، هيي نيست
Nothing will happen to you.
هيي نيست
The sun, the moon, the stars... are all yours.
خورشيد ، ماه، ستاره... همه مال شماست.
Pawan...
اون
I have become the greatest emperor.
من تبديل به بزرترين امراتورميشم.
The mightiest ruler.
mightiest حاکم.
I have won it all.
فقط من يروزم
I have also destroyed it all.
من هم شکست خوردم.
What did I win?
طور يروز شدم؟
What can Emperors win? Only wealth, land and kingdoms.
يه امراتور يروز ي داره؟ تنها ثروت ، زمين و ادشاهي.
My destiny transcends an Emperor's.
سرنوشت من  فراتر از امراتوريه .
My destiny will be that of a traveler's...
سرنوشت من در سفر کردنه..
who completes his journey.
سفري که بايد تمام کنم
And today I start my journey.
وامروز تازه آغاز سفر من است
Ajourney of love, peace and nonviolence.
با عشق و صلح ، بدون خشونت ..